Alright, hello everyone, welcome back from Thanksgiving.
好的，大家好，欢迎从感恩节回来。
Can anyone hear me?
有人能听到我说话吗？
Yep good.
是的。
Good, alright, today I want to talk about networking
好的，今天我想谈谈网络，
and how it relates to operating systems.
以及它与操作系统的关系。
And a lot of this is a geared towards lab, last lab,
这节课大部分是为最后一个实验的准备，
which you actually build some network interface driver,
你可以构建一个网络接口驱动程序，
some of this care for general understanding of
其中一些考虑的是
how the network software typically setup in operating systems
网络软件如何在操作系统中设置，
and then we're going to talk about the today's paper on live lock
然后我们将讨论今天的关于活锁的论文，
which illustrates a interesting danger in network stack design.
它描述了一个在网络堆栈设计中的有趣的危险。
So, first let me set the general scene by drawing a few network pictures,
所以，首先让我画几张关于网络的图，
network of course connects different hosts,
网络可以连接不同的主机，
at there's kind of two ways in which you can view the connections is occurring.
可以通过两种方式查看连接是否正在发生。
One is that in for nearby hosts,
第一，对于附近的主机，
they are often connected to what you what's essentially a same network.
它们通常连接到相同的网络。
So there may be a single Ethernet,
可能是一个以太网，
and maybe this is a switch or a cable
或者一个交换机或电缆，
and you might have a bunch of hosts connected to this, this Ethernet,
可能有一堆主机连接到这个以太网，
where hosts are maybe laptops or servers
主机可能是笔记本或服务器，
or as it will run routers,
或者是路由器，
and the way network software designed is
网络软件的设计方式是，
to kind of try to ignore as much as possible
为了尽可能地忽略
the details of exactly what this network is that directly attaches hosts,
网络连接主机的具体细节，
might be a single cable,
可能是一根电缆，
which is probably the case at the time today's paper was written,
可能在今天的论文发表的时候就是这样的，
this might be an Ethernet switch,
这也可能是以太网交换机，
this might be some sort of WiFi wireless Lan,
或者可能是 WiFi 无线局域网，
and these these things aren't wires at all, but rather radio links.
这些甚至根本不是线，而是无线链路。
but, for the most part
但是，在很大程度上，
these these differences in sort of exactly what the local connectivity is
这些本地连接的差异是，
a kind of totally papered over at pretty low level, in the networking stack.
在网络堆栈中，一种在很低的级别。
And so on each of these hosts,
在这些主机上，
there may be different applications,
可能有不同的应用程序，
maybe there's a web browser here
可能这里有一个网络浏览器，
and you know http server over here
这里有一个 http 服务器，
and they need to talk to each other across this network.
它们通过这个网络进行交互。
You know there's a limit to how big you can build a single local area network,
你可以建立一个局域网的规模是有限制的，
so, you know for which the abbreviation is usually LAN local area network
它的缩写是 LAN 局域网，
and the way to think about it maybe is
考虑这个问题的方法是，
that a local area network can be as large as
一个局域网可以大到，
a network in which it makes sense for all the host
在网络中的所有主机，
to be able to see all of each other's packets,
能够收到彼此的数据包，
that is sometimes hosts need to want to broadcast to all of the local hosts,
有时主机想要向所有本地主机广播，
you know that works fine with a dozen or twenty or fifty or maybe even a hundred hosts,
这对十几个、二十个、五十个甚至一百个主机都很有效，
but you can't really easily build single networks
但是你不能简单地建立一个网络，
where all the hosts can more or less directly talk to each other,
在那里所有的主机都可以直接交互，
with more than, say a few hundred hosts.
比如说超过几百个主机。
And so to deal with the way the larger Internet is constructed is
所以，更大的互联网的构建方式是，
that there's a number of these individual LANs,
有很多这样的局域网，
may be one of MIT,
可能是在麻省理工，
you know, maybe one at Harvard,
也可能在哈佛，
maybe one faraway at Stanford.
也可能是在遥远的斯坦福。
And, there's some sort of connectivity between them
在它们之间有某种连接，
which you can think of as routers,
你可以把它想象成路由器，
so there might be a router,
所以这里可能有一台路由器，
that's plugged into the MIT local area network,
在麻省理工的局域网里，
and also has perhaps a longer link to the to the Harvard network
也可能有一个长的连接到哈佛的网络，
and in fact there's a network of routers,
实际上，有一个由路由器组成的网络，
which is essentially the backbone of the Internet
它是互联网的主干，
including long-distance router to router links,
包括远程路由器到路由器的链路，
so there might be a longer link across the country
在全国范围内可能会有更长的链路，
and maybe this router is plugged into the some local area network at Stanford
可能这台路由器在斯坦福的某个局域网，
and then we have host which have this sort of more elaborate task
我们的主机有更精细的任务，
in which we want to host at MIT
我们希望麻省理工的主机，
to be able to talk to a sequence of routers to a host of Stanford
能够与斯坦福主机的路由器交互，
and this is called routing,
这就是所谓的路由，
so we need to have a way for host at MIT
所以麻省理工的主机需要一种方法
to address to name individual host Stanford
寻址斯坦福的主机，
and we need some way to,
我们需要一些方法，
so that routers near MIT can look at a packet sent by MIT
麻省理工附近的路由器可以查看麻省理工发出的数据包，
and say oh that's a packet for for Harvard,
找出这是发往哈佛的数据包，
a packet for Stanford,
或是发往斯坦福的包，
a packet that needs to go somewhere in Japan
或者是发往日本某个地方的包，
or who knows what.
或者其他什么地方。
So, from the point of view of network protocols,
那么从网络协议的角度来讲，
this local, this local communication is taken care of by Ethernet protocols,
这个本地通信是由以太网协议负责，
and this long-distance communication is sort of layered on top of that
而这种远程通信在上层的，
and taken care of by IP or Internet protocols,
由 IP 或互联网协议来负责，
that know how to route over long distances to distant hosts.
它知道如何路由到远程主机。
Okay, this is what network looks like in a nutshell.
好的，这就是网络大概的样子，
I'm would now want to talk about the what's inside packets,
现在我想讨论一下数据包里的东西，
that move across an Ethernet or move across the larger Internet,
它在以太网上移动或在更大的互联网上移动，
with an eye to eventually talking about the software that in hosts,
着眼于最终讨论主机中的软件，
that has to process hosts and routers has to process those packets.
主机和路由器必须处理这些包。
So let me start with the lowest level
所以，让我从最底层开始，
and talk about what's inside an Ethernet packet.
讨论以太网数据包中的内容。
So, when two hosts,
所以，当两台主机，
that are quite nearby attached to the same cable or same WiFi network or same Ethernet
它们连接到同一电缆、同一 WiFi 网络或同一以太网，
want to talk to each other,
想要相互通信，
the sort of lowest level protocol,
一种最底层的协议，
which allows two hosts on the same LAN to talk to each other is the Ethernet protocol
允许同一个局域网上两台主机相互通信的是以太网协议，
and you can think of one host,
你可以想象一台主机，
host 1 sending a frame over the over the Ethernet to host 2,
主机 1 通过以太网发送一个帧到主机 2 ，
what's called an Ethernet frame,
即所谓的以太网帧，
which is the Ethernet work for packet
它是在以太网工作的数据包，
and it's a series of bytes
它是一串字节，
that are sent over the Ethernet from one host to another
通过以太网从一台主机发送到另一台主机，
and what the ethernet protocol does is
而以太网协议所做的是
have just enough information in it
在其中包含足够的信息
to allow the two hosts to realize who's talking to each other
让两个主机知道在与谁交互，
and cause the host to be able to recognize packets that are addressed to them.
并且使主机能够识别寻址到它们的数据包。
And so what an Ethernet header looks,
所以以太网报头看起来是什么样子，
so the way that Ethernet deals with this is
以太网处理这个问题的方式是，
that every Ethernet packet has at the beginning a header,
每个以太网数据包的开头都有一个报头，
that has three fields, followed by some Ethernet payload,
它有三个字段，以及一些以太网有效载荷，
and what's in the header is two Ethernet addresses,
报头有两个以太网地址，
we'll call them the destination address and the source address
我们称它们为目的地址和源地址，
and also the type of the packet,
还有数据包的类型，
each of these addresses is just a 48 bit number,
每个地址只是一个 48 位的数字，
that uniquely identifies a particular network interface card really,
唯一地标识特定的网卡，
and this type field is going to indicate to the recipient host
这个类型字段向接收主机表示应该如何处理这个包，
what it's supposed to do with that packet
它如何处理数据包，
and what that really means is
它的实际意义是，
what higher level protocol should examine and process the payload of that Ethernet packet.
以哪种更高级别的协议检查和处理这个以太网数据包的有效载荷。
So, these, these are bits that go are typically set to go over the wire, piece,
这些位通常被设置为分块通过线路，
48 plus 48 plus 16 bits of header
48 加 48 加 16 位报头，
and then however much payload
然后是有效载荷，
and not really visible to the software,
并且对于软件来说是不可见的，
but there's going to be something at the beginning of the packet,
但是在包的开头会有一些东西，
that's recognized at a very low level by the hardware
由硬件在非常低的级别上识别，
that signifies the start of a packet
表示数据包的开始，
and the receiving host needs to know the packet ends,
而接收主机需要知道包结束，
so there's going to be another special bit pattern at the end,
所以在结束会有另一个特殊的位模式，
that signifies the end of the packet.
表示数据包的结束。
These two begin and end flags are never seen by the software,
这两个开始和结束标志永远不会被软件看到，
but the rest, the rest of this Ethernet frame
但是剩下的以太网帧
is delivered by the network interface card that Nic at H2 by the software.
到 H2 的网卡是由软件完成的。
If you've looked at the final lab for the course,
如果你看这门课的最后的实验，
you'll see that the software we give you includes a bunch of new files,
你会看到我们给你的软件包含了一些新文件，
including kernel/net.h
包括 kernel/net.h ，
which contains a whole bunch of definitions of packet headers for different network protocols,
包含了用于不同网络协议的报头的一整套定义，
and so this is just text taken directly from net.h file we give you
这是直接取自我们给你的 net.h 文件的内容，
and it includes description of the layout of the Ethernet header,
它包括对以太网报头的布局的描述，
and this this software we give you actually uses literally uses this struct definition,
我们给你的软件使用这个结构体定义，
in order to parse incoming Ethernet packets
用来解析传入的以太网数据包，
is to pick apart the head to get the destination and type,
从报头中获取目的地址和类型字段，
then also uses this structure to format packets.
然后也使用这个结构体来格式化包。
So the host is really in charge of
所以，主机实际上负责
sort of setting up and parsing this header, that's used by Ethernet.
设置和解析以太网使用的报头。
Any questions about Ethernet packets?
关于以太网数据包有什么问题吗？
Yeah, I have a question.
是的，我有个问题。
Please.
请。
Is is the bit pattern you mentioned
您提到的位模式，
that the hardware uses to determine the start and end of a packet
硬件使用它来确定数据包的开始和结束，
similar to the eop in the lab,
类似于实验中的 eop ，
which is a end of packet.
也就是数据包的结束。
No, no, the eop is a separate mechanism
不， eop 是一个独立机制，
between the driver and the NIC to help them communicate.
在驱动程序和网卡之间，以帮助它们进行通信。
This is, there's some electrical schemes,
有一些电路方案，
some low level electrical or optical signaling scheme
一些底层的电或光信号方案
to transmit bits over Ethernet cables,
用于在以太网电缆上传输位，
and these flags have to do with the,
这些标志必须，
typically, electrical patterns that would not be legal inside a packet
通常，这种电信号模式在数据包中是非法的，
and so you know one scheme is to
所以，一种方案是，
instead of just sending zero one bits over the wire,
除了在线路上只发送 0 或 1 的位，
you can send you could send sequences of two signals,
你可以发送两个信号序列，
so there's four different symbols possible
所以有四种不同的符号，
with sequences of two different electrical voltage levels or something
有两个不同的电压水平的序列或别的什么，
and have two of the four possible symbols indicate 0 or 1 bits
四种信号中的两种表示 0 或 1 位，
in the body of the packet
在数据包的主体中，
and have the remaining two indicate begin and end.
而使用其余的两种来表示开始和结束。
That was in fact a scheme that was used years ago,
实际上，这就是几年前用过的方案，
scheme much like that was used years ago Ethernet,
几年前以太网就使用过类似的方案，
I don't actually know how it works now.
我不知道它现在是怎么工作的。
Okay, something to know about these addresses is that
好的，关于这些地址需要知道的是
what these are 48 bit addresses,
这些 48 位地址是什么，
the reason for the 48 bits is that
48 位的原因是，
they wanted to make sure that there was enough bits
想要确保有足够的位，
to be able to give a unique address to every different NIC ever manufactured.
能够为曾经制造的每个不同的网卡提供唯一的地址，
So there's a vast number of possible addresses,
所以有大量的地址，
the internal structure of these 48 bit addresses is that
这 48 位地址的内部结构是
the first half, the first 24 bits is a manufacturer number
前半部分的 24 位是制造商编号，
and there's every manufacturer network interface cards NICs has its own manufacturer number,
每个网卡制造商都有自己的制造商编号，
so that's the first 24 bits,
这就是前 24 位，
and the second 24 bits is
第二部分 24 位是
just any number can be any unique number assigned by the manufacturers,
由制造商分配的任意唯一数字，
manufacturers typically assign them in just ascending orders,
制造商通常按升序分配它们，
if you buy you know half a dozen network interface cards,
如果你购买 6 个网卡，
the network interface card, each network interface card has programmed into its own address,
每个网卡已经编程为自己的地址，
and if you look at the address,
如果你看一下地址，
you'll see that the high bits are the same
你会发现它们高位是相同的，
for these six cards you bought from the same manufacturer,
这些你从同一制造商购买的 6 个网卡，
but the low 24 bits are probably six sequential numbers.
而低 24 位可能是 6 个连续的编号。
So these addresses are unique,
所以这些地址是唯一的，
but what they're not helpful in is locating the destination host,
但他们没有帮助定位目的主机，
so if you know the host you're talking about is on the same local area network,
所以，如果你知道正在交互的主机位于同一局域网上，
as you you can use Ethernet address
你可以使用以太网地址，
and it's on the same local area network.
并且它位于相同的局域网上。
So we'll be listening for packet with his own address,
所以我们会监听它自己地址的包，
but if the hosts are trying to talk to on the other side of the country,
但如果主机想与国家另一边的交互，
you have to use a different scheme,
你必须使用不同的方案，
and that's what's IP is all about,
这就是 IP 的相关内容，
I'll talk about in a bit.
我稍后会谈到。
Okay, so this is what these packets look like,
好的，这就是这些包的样子，
you can actually look at Ethernet packets in action using the tcpdump program
你可以使用 tcpdump 查看运行中的以太网包，
and you're encouraged to do this,
我们鼓励你这样做，
you probably need to do this as part of the lab.
你可能需要在实验中用到。
And this is actually the output of tcpdump from the lab,
这是来自实验的 tcpdump 的输出，
and what tcpdump is telling us here was telling us a whole bunch of things,
tcpdump 在这里告诉我们一系列事情，
this first part is the time at which the packet arrived,
第一部分是数据包到达的时间。
if you like you can try this on your laptops,
如果你愿意，可以在你的笔记本电脑上试一下，
if you install tcpdump,
如果安装了 tcpdump ，
and the rest of the first line is a sort of human readable interpretation
第一行的其余部分是一种人类可读的说明，
of what kind of packet that is
说明这是一种什么样的数据包，
and then these next three lines or the part here is
然后接下来的三行或这里的部分是
a hex dump of the of the received packet
接收到的数据包的十六进制，
and you can see,
你可以看到，
we can actually follow along with the Ethernet header,
我们可以跟随以太网报头，
there's these first 48 bits or six bytes is a broadcast address, all fs
前 48 位或 6 个字节是广播地址，全是 f ，
and all fs Ethernet address is broadcast to all the hosts on the local network.
全是 f 的以太网地址是广播到本地网络上的所有主机（的地址）。
The next 48 bits is the sending hosts Ethernet address
接下来的 48 位是发送主机的以太网地址，
which you know we can't necessarily tell anything about although the high bits mean,
我们不能告诉你高位的含义，
in fact, this was generated by xv6 we're under QEMU,
实际上，这是我们在 QEMU 中由 xv6 生成的，
so no real NIC was involved,
所以没有真正的网卡，
so it's not actually a manufacturer number appears something that QEMU makes up.
所以它实际上不是一个制造商编号，而是 QEMU 编造的。
And then the next 16 bits, the next two bytes is the type,
然后接下来的 16 位，接下来的 2 个字节是类型，
it's the Ethernet type of the packet,
它是数据包的以太网类型，
in this case, it's 0806 which is a protocol called ARP,
在这种情况下，它是 0806 ，是一个叫做 ARP 的协议，
which I'll talk about in a moment.
我稍后会谈到这一点。
And the rest of this stuff is, is the payload of an ARP packet,
其余的东西就是一个 ARP 包的有效载荷，
we shall also talk about.
我们也会讲到。
Any questions about what were we're looking at here?
关于我们在这里看到的，有没有什么问题？
This well worth trying out on your own computer,
这很值得在你的计算机上试一下，
if you care about networks.
如果你想了解网络。
Okay, so the next protocol that's of relevance to the lab
好的，下一个与实验相关的协议，
and communication over Ethernet is called arp.
通过以太网通信的称为 ARP 。
So at the Ethernet level,
所以，在以太网级别，
every host has a 48 Ethernet address,
每台主机都有一个 48 位以太网地址，
but for communicating over the Internet,
但要在互联网上通信，
it turns out you need to use a 32 bit Internet address
你需要使用 32 位互联网地址，
and the reason why Internet addresses are different is that
互联网地址不同的原因是，
Internet addresses have internal structure in a 32 bit,
互联网地址的内部结构有 32 位，
the hosts 32 bit Internet address,
主机 32 位互联网地址，
the high bits are full of all kinds of hints
高位都是各种线索，
about where in the entire Internet this packet needs to go.
这个数据包需要去互联网的哪里。
And so you can think of an Internet address as having a high bits a network number,
所以你可以认为互联网地址是一个高位的网络号，
it's actually a little more complex than that,
实际上要比这复杂一点，
but it's essentially a network number,
但它本质上是一个网络编号，
every network in the Internet has a distinct number
互联网中的每个网络都有一个不同的编号，
and routers look at these the high bits and the Internet address
路由器查看这些高位和互联网地址，
to decide which router and the Internet this packet needs to be forwarded to
用来确定需要将数据包转发到哪个路由器或互联网，
and then the low bits in a 32 bit Internet Internet address IP address are
然后互联网地址 IP 地址中的 32 个低位是，
the number of that of the host we want to talk to on its local network.
我们想要在本地网络中交互的主机编号。我们想通过它的本地网络与之交谈。
But when a packet finally arrives,
但是当数据包最终到达时，
and when the Internet packet arrives at Ethernet,
当互联网数据包到达以太网时，
we need some way to give in on 32 bit IP address,
我们需要方法在给出的 32 位 IP 地址上，
figure out the 48 bit Ethernet address of that host.
找出那个主机的 48 位以太网地址。
And the way the Internet chooses to do that is to have a dynamic resolution protocol,
互联网这样做的方法是使用动态解析协议，
kind of request response protocol called ARP, for address resolution protocol
一种称为 ARP 的请求响应协议，用于地址解析协议，
and the way to think about it is that
考虑这一点的方法是，
when a IP packet arrives at a router
当 IP 数据包到达路由器时，
or its needs to be sent by a host
或者它需要由主机发送，
to a host that's known to be on the same LAN local area network,
发往同一局域网上的主机，
the sender first broadcasts on that LAN, an ARP packet,
发送者首先在局域网上广播一个 ARP 数据包，
that's a request that says whoever has whoever owns this IP address,
请求谁拥有这个 IP 地址，
please respond with your 48 Ethernet address
请回复你的 48 位以太网地址，
and assuming that host exists is turned on,
如果主机存在并打开，
it will respond with an ARP response packet.
它将使用 ARP 响应数据包进行响应。
And this is the format of the packet of an ARP packet,
这是 ARP 数据包的格式，
the way it actually shows up is inside an Ethernet packet
它实际显示的方式是在以太网数据包内部，
and so what you would actually see
所以你实际上会看到的是，
and the network is first the Ethernet header,
网络首先是 48 位以太网报头，
which has the 48 bit source field,
有 48 位源地址，
48 bit destination field,
48 位目的地址，
its destination source type,
它的目的源类型，
so this is the Ethernet header.
这就是以太网报头。
And then, from the Ethernet point of view,
然后，从以太网的角度来看，
the rest is payload,
其余的是有效载荷，
but actually in the Ethernet payload is ARP packet,
但其实以太网有效载荷是 ARP 数据包，
which has these fields,
它具有这些字段，
boom boom boom right after the Ethernet header.
紧跟在以太网报头之后。
And the way the receiving host knows on our packet is
而接收主机知道数据包的方式是，
by looking at this type field,
通过查看这个类型字段，
and if it's 0806,
如果是 0806 ，
that's the agreed on Ethernet protocol number for ARP
那就是 ARP 的以太网协议编号，
and then the receiving host software would know
然后接收主机软件知道，
to hand this packet to its ARP protocol processing code.
将这个包交给 ARP 协议处理代码。
What's in these packets
这些包里有什么，
and there's a bunch of junk here
这里有一些东西，
that basically amounts to saying I have an Internet address,
表示我有一个互联网地址，
I want to turn it into an Ethernet address,
我想把它变成以太网地址，
please respond if you own this Internet address,
如果你拥有这个互联网地址，请回复，
and then, these fields hold the Internet and Ethernet addresses,
然后，这些字段保存互联网和以太网地址，
of whatever host is sending this ARP packet
由这个 ARP 数据包的主机发送的，
and that's enough to figure out the [] whose to build dynamically tables,
这可以计算出[]用来构建动态列表，
that tell them the correspondence between Ethernet and IP addresses.
告诉它们以太网和 IP 地址之间的对应关系。
Again, we can use tcpdump in order to see these packets go by,
同样，我们可以使用 tcpdump 来查看这些数据包经过，
highly likely to see them if you run tcpdump,
如果你运行 tcpdump ，很可能会看到它们，
here's again a tcpdump that taken from the lab,
这又是一个来自实验的 tcpdump ，
it turns out that in the lab,
在实验里，
you know your xv6 will end up talking a simulated to, but talking Ethernet protocol
xv6 最终会与模拟的以太网协议交互，
and sending IP packets through Ethernet through a simulated Ethernet protocol,
通过模拟以太网协议发送 IP 数据包，
with whatever host you're running QEMU on.
在你运行 QEMU 的任何主机上运行。
And so when you want you'll actually be able to see these ARP exchanges,
所以，你可以看到这些 ARP 报文，
between xv6 and your host
在 xv6 和你们的主机之间，
and so what we're seeing here is
我们在这里看到的是
my host wants knows the IP address of my xv6
我的主机想知道我的 xv6 的 IP 地址，
and wants to wants to figure out its Ethernet address on the LAN that QEMU simulates.
想要知道它在 QEMU 模拟的局域网中的以太网地址。
And this second packet is my xv6
第二个包是我的 xv6 ，
and you can see the code that generates is my xv6 has seen this request,
你可以看到生成的代码是我的 xv6 看到了这个请求，
realize that it's the owner of the IP address in the request
意识到它是请求中 IP 地址的所有者，
and is sending back the response,
并且正在发回响应，
tcpdump is nicely parsed out the fields in the ARP packet
tcpdump 可以很好地解析出 ARP 数据包中的字段，
and printed them here,
并打印在这里，
and I think this is the sender's IP address,
我想这是发送者的 IP 地址，
and this is the,
这是，
sorry, this is the sender's IP address,
抱歉，这是发送者的 IP 地址，
this is the IP address that the sender is interested in
这是发送者感兴趣的 IP 地址，
and those would presumably going here and here
这些东西大概会放在这里和这里，
and this is a response
这是一个响应，
with the Ethernet address of the owner of this IP address,
是具有这个 IP 地址的所有者的以太网地址，
and this Ethernet address probably end up being in this field,
并且这个以太网地址可能最终在这个字段中，
and if we're clever enough,
如果我们足够聪明，
we can pick apart these packets and see some of these fields,
我们可以把这些数据包拆开，看看其中的一些字段，
as we know, this part is the Ethernet header,
如我们所知，这个部分是以太网报头，
destination Ethernet address, source Ethernet address and packet type 0806,
目的以太网地址，源以太网地址和数据包类型 0806 ，
working backwards,
向后看，
this is the tip field,
这是 tip 字段，
which is the IP address that the sender wants to find the Ethernet address for
它是发送者想要查找以太网地址的 IP 地址，
and if you pick this apart,
如果你把这个拆开，
there's one byte, for each of the four fields of the IP address,
这里有一个字节，每个 IP 地址有四个字段，
sorry, it's really looking for 10.0.2.15,
抱歉，它是在找 10.0.2.15 ，
this is 10 hex, 0 hex, 2 hex, 15 hex
这是十六进制 10 ，十六进制 0 ，十六进制 2 ，十六进制 15 ，
and then there's the targets Ethernet address which is not known
然后是目标以太网地址，它是未知的，
and then the sender's IP address 10.0.2.2
然后是发送者的 IP 地址 10.0.2.2 ，
and the senders Ethernet address
发送者的以太网地址，
and a bunch of other junk here saying that
这里还有一堆东西在说，
we're interested in Ethernet and IP address formats.
我们对以太网和 IP 地址格式感兴趣。
And there's this request, this response,
并且这是请求，这是回应，
any questions about ARP?
关于 ARP ，有什么问题吗？
Um, yeah question,
嗯，是的，有个问题，
why is it necessary for the sender to include its IP address,
为什么发送者需要包括它的 IP 地址，
if it if it's Ethernet addresses already included in the packet,
如果它已经包含在数据包中的以太网地址，
like to respond to it,
想要响应它，
wouldn't it wouldn't the receiver only need using that address.
那么接收者是不是只需要使用那个地址？
Yeah, I don't know why that all this stuff's in there,
是的，我不知道为什么里面会有这些东西，
I think if you wanted to,
我想如果你想的话，
you could strip this down quite a bit,
你可以把这件事做得更简单，
you know like that, sent,
比如，发送，
well, okay, maybe the answer is that
好吧，也许答案是，
this protocol was designed to be usable on networks other than Ethernet
这个协议被设计成在网络上使用而不是在以太网，
and so it was designed to be fairly self-contained,
所以它被设计成相当独立的，
so that it didn't depend on anything in the, didn't depend on anything else
所以它不依赖于其他任何东西，
and therefore the ARP header has a copy of the Ethernet addresses,
所以， ARP 报头具有以太网地址的复制，
that in fact if you know you're sending ARP over Ethernet,
事实上，如果你通过以太网发送 ARP ，
the Ethernet packet also has all the Ethernet address,
以太网数据包还要包含所有的以太网地址，
as you can see here,
正如你在这里看到的，
so, it's redundant to be running ARP over Ethernet,
所以，在以太网上运行 ARP 是多余的，
but maybe if you are running ARP over something else,
但如果你在其他地方运行 ARP ，
you'll need these fields,
你需要这些字段，
because maybe something else packet format,
因为可能还有其他数据包格式，
doesn't have the, doesn't already include these addresses.
没有包括这些地址。
I see, okay, thank you.
我明白了，好的，谢谢。
Oh, sorry, what is that part on the right versions, are you.
哦，抱歉，右边那部分是什么？
Okay, this, this is not interesting yet,
好的，这个，这不是很有趣，
but this is ASCII interpretation of these bytes,
但这是这些字节的 ASCII 码解释，
so, well, the dot here corresponds to you know a byte that has no ASCII equivalent,
这个点对应没有 ASCII 码的字节，
and this I guess somewhere in here, 52 or 55 probably,
我猜这个可能是 52 或 55 ，
52 probably R and 55 is probably U in ASCII,
在 ASCII 码中， 52 可能是 R ， 55 可能是 U ，
so this would be more interesting
所以，这会更有趣，
when we start sending packets that have actual ASCII text in them,
当我们开始发送包含 ASCII 文本的数据包时，
rather than binary fields.
而不是二进制字段。
Okay I see, thank you.
好的，我明白了，谢谢。
Yes.
好的。
Okay, and I'm showing you this,
好的，我给你看这个，
because you'll see these packets in the lab.
因为你会在实验里看到这些包。
Okay, actually, there's something I wanted to.
好吧，有件事我想。
Well, there's something I want to make sure,
好的，我有件事想确认一下，
that you are caught in this discussion
你能从这个讨论中获得，
and that's the [habit] in formatting packets of nesting protocols and nesting headers,
这是嵌套协议和嵌套报头的格式化数据包的[习惯]，
so so, what we just saw was a packet that Ethernet header and Ethernet payload,
所以我们刚才看到一个数据包，以太网报头和以太网有效载荷，
the first part of the Ethernet payload was you know an ARP header,
以太网有效负载的第一部分是 ARP 报头，
and as it happens ARP you know remaining payload,
剩下的部分是 ARP 有效载荷，
but there are other,
但是还有其他的，
what we'll see in a moment is much more complicated structures,
我们稍后会看到更复杂的结构，
which in Ethernet packet that contains an IP packet
在以太网数据包中包含 IP 数据包，
and inside the IP packet is a UDP packet
在 IP 包内部是 UDP 包，
and so UDP is another protocol that you can run over IP,
UDP 是另一种可以在 IP 上运行的协议，
so there's a UDP header,
所以这里有一个 UDP 报头，
it also,
它也是，
you know not necessarily have to understand these acronyms yet,
不一定要理解这些首字母缩写，
but as UDP header,
但作为 UDP 报头，
a UDP packet also has a header and a payload
UDP 数据包也包含报头和有效载荷，
and there's times when used to carry another protocol inside UDP,
有时会在 UDP 中携带另一个协议，
so for example the domain name system,
比如域名系统，
has yet another format of packet define that fits inside UDP,
包含另一种适合在 UDP 内部的数据包格式定义，
so what you see is
所以你看到的是，
that hosts are sending packets will build up a packet,
主机发送数据包将构建一个数据包，
the DNS software will say I want to send a packet over UDP,
DNS 软件会说我想通过 UDP 发送数据包，
the UDP software will prepare the UDP header,
UDP 软件会准备 UDP 报头，
we send that over IP,
我们通过 IP 发送，
the IP software will prepend an IP header,
IP 软件会添加 IP 报头，
the Ethernet software will prepend Ethernet header,
以太网软件会添加以太网报头，
and gradually build up packets in in that software when it's sending.
并在发送时逐渐在软件中建立数据包。
And similarly when system receives packets,
类似地，当系统接收到数据包时，
it first gets the whole packet,
它首先获得整个数据包，
inspects the first header and notice Ethernet,
检查第一个报头，注意到是以太网，
because it receives it from Ethernet NIC,
因为它从以太网卡接收数据，
checksum validity, strips off this header
校验有效性，去除这个报头，
to look at the next header,
查看下一个报头，
there will be a type this you always a type field
这里总有一个类型，
or in this case, the protocol field,
或者在这种情况下，有一个协议字段，
that tells the software what to expect after the Ethernet header.
告诉软件在以太网报头之后希望发生什么。
So there's a type field that indicates IP versus ARP,
所以，有一个类型字段表示 IP 或 ARP ，
so this the software will look at each header,
所以，软件将查看每个报头，
validate it, strip it off, revealing the next header,
验证它，剥离它，获取下一个报头，
you know check that header, interpret it, figure out what it means, strip it off,
检查报头，解释它，理解它，再把它去掉，
revealing the next and hand it on to the next layer of software.
暴露出下一层，并将其传递给下一层软件。
I'll talk a bit more about this,
我会更多地讨论这一点，
but this is a sort of universal way of looking at nested packet headers.
但这是一种看待嵌套数据报头的通用方式。
Alright, so the Ethernet packet, the Ethernet header,
好的，以太网数据包，以太网报头，
is enough to get packet to a host on local area network,
足以将数据包发送到局域网上的主机，
when especially when and if you want to send an IP packet locally,
特别是当你想在本地发送 IP 数据包时，
you can use ARP,
你可以使用 ARP ，
but IP is used much more generally,
但 IP 是更通用的，
IP that a sort of layer of the protocol,
IP 是一种协议层，
that helps you deliver a packet anywhere in the Internet,
帮助你将数据包传送到互联网的任何位置，
based on IP addresses.
基于 IP 地址。
And so this is the format of an IP packet,
所以，这是 IP 数据包的格式，
again taken you can find it in net.h at the source we give you
再次，你可以在我们给你的 net.h 源码中找到它，
and over Ethernet [],
通过以太网[]，
the way you see, this is,
你可以看到，这是，
in an Ethernet packet with a destination source and type of,
在以太网数据包中，有目的地址、源地址和类型，
Ethernet type equals 0800
以太网类型等于 0800 ，
and then the IP header, and then IP payload,
然后是 IP 报头，以及 IP 有效载荷，
when you send a packet to a distant network,
当你将数据包发送到远程网络时，
you know on the other side of the world,
在世界的另一边的网络，
the IP header gets passed along,
IP 报头传递，
this Ethernet header gets stripped off after you leave the local Ethernet,
在离开本地以太网后，以太网报头被剥离，
maybe a new one gets put on it for each hop that your packet is routed,
也许在路由数据包的每一跳上都会放上一个新的，
but the IP header stays basically the same,
但是 IP 报头保持不变，
the whole way from the [] the original source host in your computer,
从你的计算机上的原始源主机，
all the way to the destination host,
一直到目的主机，
this header has global significance,
这个报头具有全局意义，
where as the Ethernet header is really only used for each, for a single local area network,
而以太网报头仅用于单个局域网，
so there has to be enough information here
所以，这里必须有足够的信息
to carry a packet all the way to the far side of the Internet.
将数据包一路传送到互联网的另一端。
And the critical fields for our purposes
对于我们的目的来说，关键字段是，
really three very interesting fields in this packet format,
这个数据包格式中的三个非常有趣的字段，
the destination field, which is the 32 bit IP address of the host,
目的地址字段，是主机的 32 位 IP 地址，
that we want to send the packet to,
我们将数据包发送到，
in particular in its high bits,
特别是在它的高位，
it's going to have network numbers in it that'll help routers
其中包含网络编号，用于帮助路由器，
and when the packet is delivered,
当数据包被递送时，
this p protocol field will tell the destination host what to do with the packet,
这个 p 协议字段告诉目的地主机如何处理数据包，
you know what to do with it next after it strips off the IP header.
在它剥离 IP 报头之后下一步该如何处理。
If you ever seen a MIT IP address,
如果你见过麻省理工的 IP 地址，
you'll see, well there's a couple different ones,
你会看到有几个不同的，
but for example if you see Internet address starting with 18,
但是如果你看到互联网地址以 18 开头，
this the things have actually changed in the last couple years,
在过去的几年里，事情发生了变化，
but this for a long time was the network number of MIT
但在很长一段时间里，这是麻省理工的网络编号，
and so most hosted MIT would have IP addresses whose high byte was 18
所以，大多数托管麻省理工的 IP 地址的高位字节是 18 ，
and routers all over the world would have some table,
世界各地的路由器都会有一张表，
they'd look up 18
它们会查到 18 ，
and say aha I know how to route this packet one step closer to MIT.
然后说，我知道如何路由这个数据包到麻省理工又近一步。
So let me, let me show you again tcpdump output,
所以，让我再次展示 tcpdump 的输出，
again actually taken from the lab, that includes IP header.
同样取自实验，其中包括 IP 报头。
Okay, so we can parse this packet,
好的，我们可以解析这个数据包，
because it was sent over the Ethernet,
因为它是通过以太网发送的，
it starts with an Ethernet header.
它以以太网报头开始。
It actually one,
它是一，
I think it's kind of wrong with these tcpdump
我认为这些 tcpdump 是有问题的，
with these packets that are generated and,
这些生成的包，
now that I'm seeing it, I'm not sure what the problem is,
现在我看它，我不确定问题出在哪里，
they should not start with all,
它们不应该开头，
these Ethernet headers shouldn't start with all fs,
以太网报头不应该以全部 f 开始，
because it's broadcast address,
因为它是广播地址，
that cause the packet to go to every host
这会导致数据包到达每台主机，
and you would not see that for a packet sent between two individual hosts
你不会看到在两台单独的主机之间发送的数据包，
as this one is on a real network,
因为这台主机位于真实网络上，
there's something funny going on with my solution to the network lab with QEMU,
在 QEMU 的网络实验中我的解决方案中有些东西有点滑稽，
anyway we have the Ethernet destination address, Ethernet source address
不管怎样，我们有以太网目的地址、以太网源地址，
and the Ethernet type is 0800
而以太网类型是 0800 ，
is means that the remaining bytes are IP packet,
表示剩余的字节是 IP 数据包，
the IP packet header length I think it's 20 bytes,
IP 数据包报头长度我认为是 20 字节，
[] find the end,
找到结尾，
two fifteen,
二，十五，
so this must be the end of the IP header.
所以这一定是 IP 报头的结尾。
And working backwards, because these are the fields, we really care about,
往回看一下，因为这些是我们真正关心的字段，
the destination IP field is a is 10, 10.0.2.2,
目的 IP 字段是， a 是 10 ， 10.0.2.2 ，
which is I think the,
我认为，
in QEMU's funny simulated network is
在 QEMU 中，有趣的模拟网络是
the address of the real computer I'm running QEMU on,
我运行 QEMU 的真实计算机的地址，
and then before that is this IP source address, which is 10.0.2.15,
在这之前是 IP 源地址，是 10.0.2.15，
which is the sender, which is QEMU's address
是发送方，是 QEMU 的地址，
for the, for xv6 basically running inside QEMU
是 QEMU 内运行的 xv6 的地址，
and then this stuff before this, all this other stuff,
然后在这之前的这些东西，
there's a sixteen bit checksum,
有一个 16 位的校验和，
which your software is supposed to check
你的软件应该检查它，
to realize that a packet has been corrupted and should be discarded,
意识到数据包已经损坏，应该丢弃，
that's this checksum,
这就是校验和，
theres one byte,
这里有一个字节，
alright, mess something up here.
好的，这里的东西乱了。
Oh, this is, this is 16, sorry, this is 16 bit checksum,
哦，抱歉，这是 16 位校验和，
this 11 is the protocol number, which is particularly important,
这个 11 是协议号，这一点特别重要，
11 hex is 16 plus 1 or 17,
十六进制 11 是 16 加 1 或者 17 ，
so that means that this is a UDP packet,
意味着这是一个 UDP 数据包，
based on that protocol field.
基于协议字段。
And then all this other stuff we don't really care about,
然后所有这些东西，我们并不关心，
as things like the length of the packet.
比如数据包的长度。
Any questions about IP headers?
关于 IP 报头，有什么问题吗？
Alright, again the critical stuff is
好的，再说一遍，这里的关键是，
the IP header has the IP address of the source and destination,
IP 报头具有 IP 地址的源地址和目的地址，
and this protocol field is going to tell the destination host's networking stack,
而这个协议字段告诉目的主机网络堆栈，
that this packet should be processed by UDP software,
这个分组应该由 UDP 软件处理，
which I'll talk about right now.
我现在会谈到这一点。
Okay, the, this this IP header,
好的，这个 IP 报头，
it's enough to get a packet to any host on the Internet,
它足以将数据包发送到互联网上的任何主机，
but we want to do better than that,
但我们想做得更好，
every host was running lots and lots of different programs that need to use the network,
每台主机都在运行很多需要使用网络的不同程序，
they need to send and receive packets in the network
它们需要在网络中发送和接收数据包，
and so we need a way that's not in the, it's not included in the IP field,
所以我们需要一种不在 IP 字段中的方法，
in order to decide which application needs to,
为了决定哪个应用程序需要，
which application on the target host its package ought to be handed off to.
应该将包移交给目标主机上的哪个应用程序。
And there's a couple of protocols that do that job,
有几个协议可以完成这项工作，
one of them is TCP quite complex,
一个是相当复杂的 TCP ，
and other is UDP.
还有其他是 UDP 。
TCP is actually what's used mostly for things like the web
TCP 主要用于 web 之类的东西，
and TCP is a very complex protocol,
TCP 是一种非常复杂的协议，
that not only helps your packet be delivered to the right application,
它不仅帮助将数据包传送到正确的应用程序，
but also has a lot of things, like sequence numbers,
还有许多东西，比如序列号，
in order to detect lost packets and re-transmit them,
为了检测丢失的包并重新发送它们，
make sure packets or data is delivered in order and without gaps,
确保包或数据按顺序而且不间断地传送，
if in case anything goes wrong.
防止出现什么问题。
UDP is a much simpler protocol,
UDP 是一种简单得多的协议，
that just delivers,
它只是传递，
sort of best effort delivery of a packet to a particular application,
尽力而为的传递包到特定应用，
but without any error correction
但是，没有任何纠错，
or basically without anything else,
或者没有任何其他东西，
for us, the critical fields are these two port numbers
对我们来说，关键字段是这两个端口号，
and the game here is that,
这里的游戏是，
when your application wants to send or receive packets,
当你的应用程序想要发送或接收数据包时，
it uses the what's called the sockets API,
它使用所谓的套接字 API ，
on Unix at any way,
在 Unix 上，
and this is a set of system calls
这是一组系统调用，
where by a process can say,
其中进程说，
look I'm interested in packets addressed to a particular port
我对寻址到特定端口的数据包感兴趣，
and it'll say what port numbers interested,
它会说感兴趣的端口号，
sorry, packets with particular,
抱歉，特定的包，
I want to receive packets with a particular destination port
我要接收具有特定目的端口的数据包，
and the operating system make a system call,
操作系统进行系统调用，
it set this up in the operating system, will return a file descriptor,
它在操作系统中设置，返回一个文件描述符，
and every time a packet arrives with the port the application asks for,
每次数据包到达应用程序请求的端口，
that packet will appear on the file descriptor
这个数据包将出现在文件描述符上，
and the application can read it.
应用程序就可以读取它。
And the these ports are really two kinds of ports,
这两个端口实际上是两种端口，
some are well-known port numbers,
一些是知名端口号，
like I think port 53 is the official well-known universally agreed port number for a DNS name server,
比如端口号 53 是 DNS 名称服务器的官方知名普遍同意的端口号，
so if you want to send a request to a DNS name server,
所以，如果你要向 DNS 名称服务器发送请求，
you can send into UDP packet addressed dport 53,
你可以通过 dport 53 发送 UDP 包，
there's a bunch of other well-known ports
还有许多其他知名的端口，
for commonly available services with universally agreed on numbers
可以提供普遍可用的服务，使用普遍同意的编号，
and then the remainings remain of the 16 bit port number space,
然后剩余的 16 位端口号空间，
is used for the sort of anonymous client ends support,
用于匿名客户端支持，
so if I want to send a packet to a DNS server,
所以，如果我想要向 DNS 服务器发送数据包，
it's dport will be 53, right,
它的 dport 是 53 ，
but its sport will be a more or less randomly chosen number for my end,
但它的 sport 是我这边随机选择的数字，
so that when that will be associated with my application's socket,
所以，它与我的应用程序的套接字相关联，
so that when the DNS server sends a reply,
所以，当 DNS 服务器发送回复时，
it will be addressed,
将对其进行寻址，
the DNS server will copy the request source port into the destination port field of the reply,
DNS 服务器会将请求源端口复制到回复的目的端口字段中，
sent it back to my machine
并将其发回我的机器，
and my machine will use this port number
我的机器将使用这个端口号
to figure out which application should get the reply.
来确定哪个应用程序应该得到响应。
Okay, so the main function here is to have these two port numbers,
好的，这里的主要功能是拥有这两个端口号，
in order to handout,
为了分发，
be able to handout packets individual applications on this machine.
可以在这台机器上分发各个应用程序的数据包。
So, feel free to ask questions.
所以，请随意提问。
I have tcpdump output for UDP also,
我也有 UDP 的 tcpdump 输出，
again taken from the lab.
也是从实验里拿来的。
So again we have a Ethernet header,
同样，我们有一个以太网报头，
and 20 bytes IP header which probably ends here,
20 字节的 IP 报头可能在这里结束，
11 is IP protocol 17 which is UDP,
11 是 IP 协议号 17 ，也就是 UDP ，
so the receiving host will know to process it with its UDP software,
所以接收主机知道用 UDP 软件来处理它，
the next 8 bytes are the UDP header which is shown right here.
接下来的 8 个字节是这里显示的 UDP 报头。
And so who knows what these port numbers are?
那么谁知道这些端口号是什么？
I mean,
我是说，
you know this, this is unfortunately a packet is generated by the lab software
这是一个由实验软件生成的数据包，
without any, any special numbers
任何特殊的号码，
and so this is the port numbers that happened to choose,
这是恰巧选择的端口号，
this must be the length of the packet,
这一定是包的长度，
1b is twenty something
1b 是二十多，
and this is my, this our software for,
这是我的，这是我们的软件，
UDP in xv6 is so lame,
xv6 中的 UDP 还很差劲，
that it doesn't fill in the checksum field,
它没有填写校验和字段，
but this is the header.
这就是报头。
And then after the UDP header is the payload of the UDP packet
然后在 UDP 报头之后是 UDP 包的有效载荷，
and in this case, the application is sending ASCII text
在这种情况下，应用程序正在发送 ASCII 文本，
and that ASCII text is right here.
而 ASCII 文本就在这里。
So this is ASCII text place inside UDP packet,
所以，这是在 UDP 数据包中 ASCII 文本，
place inside an IP packet,
在 IP 数据包中，
place inside an Ethernet packet,
又在以太网数据包中，
sent over simulated Ethernet.
通过模拟以太网发送。
Sorry, I just had a question,
抱歉，我有个问题，
so when when you when you said when you send a packet to someone,
当你说给某人寄数据包的时候，
you don't know their Ethernet like address,
你不知道它们的以太网地址，
so do you just send it to your router,
那么是否只是将它发送到你的路由器，
then the router figures out from.
然后路由器通过计算得出。
If if for most packets sent somewhere else on the Internet,
对于大多数在互联网上发送到其他地方的数据包，
let's see,
让我们看看，
your host if you send a packet to a particular IP address,
如果你将数据包发送到特定的 IP 地址，
your host software will look at the destination address
你的主机软件将查看目标地址，
to figure out if the target host is on the same local area network as you are,
确定目标主机是否与你在同一局域网上，
and if it is, it'll use ARP to translate the IP address into an Ethernet address,
如果是，它将使用 ARP 将 IP 地址转换为以太网地址，
and then send the packet over the Ethernet to the target host,
然后通过以太网将数据包发送到目标主机，
so that's what happens in the special case
所以在这种情况下，
in which the target host is on the same network.
目标主机在同一网络中。
In the more general case,
在更一般的情况下，
we're sending the packet to somewhere else on the Internet across the country,
我们将数据包发送到全国各地的互联网上的其他地方，
you'll send the packet to a router on the same local area network,
你将把数据包发送到同一局域网上的路由器，
that router will look at the destination IP address
那个路由器将查看目的 IP 地址，
to pick the next router
选择下一台路由器，
to decide which router it's attached to it for the packet to
以确定对于数据包连接到哪台路由器，
and packet go hop by hop through routers,
数据包的逐跳通过路由器，
getting closer and closer to the target.
离目标越来越近。
Does that answer your question?
这回答了你的问题吗？
OK, I see,
好的，我明白了，
yes, thank you so much.
是的，非常感谢。
Someone asked if there's a limit to the length of the packet,
有人问数据的长度是否有限制，
and the answer is yes,
答案是肯定的，
there's a couple of different limits,
有几个不同的限制，
every network every underlying network technology,
每个底层网络技术，
like Ethernet, there are other things,
比如以太网，但还有其他东西，
that are like Ethernet has its own maximum packet length,
比如以太网，有它自己的最大数据包长度，
so, when today's paper was written,
所以，当今天的论文写的时候，
the maximum packet length was on Ethernet was 1500 bytes,
以太网上的最大数据包长度是 1500 字节，
I think modern Ethernet's allow packets up to around 9000 or 10 000 bytes,
我认为现代以太网允许 9000 或 10000 字节的数据包，
but that's about the highest maximum packet size, I've heard of.
但这是我听说过的最大数据包大小。
And the reason,
这个原因，
there's a couple reasons why you wouldn't want sort of infinitely long single packets,
你不希望无限长的单个包有几个原因，
one of them is that
其中之一是，
the packets are you sending these packets over wires,
你通过线路发送这些数据包，
that could be quite long and subject to noise and interference
可能会相当长，而且会受到噪音和干扰的影响，
and so you do get corruption of bits when you're sending packets,
所以，当你发送数据包时，可能会出现位损坏，
basically, every network technology is some kind of checksum or error correcting code
基本上，每种网络技术都是某种校验和或纠错码，
that goes along with every packet,
伴随着每个数据包，
but checksums and error correcting codes are only capable
但是校验和和纠错码仅能
of reliably detecting errors over a certain number of bits,
可靠地检测一定数量的位上的错误，
which and so as you increase the number of bits,
随着位数的增加，
the probability of an uncommon error goes up and up
出现不常见错误的概率会越来越高，
and so that limits the,
所以，这限制了，
for reasonable size checksum like 16 or 32 bits,
对于合理大小的校验和，比如 16 位或 32 位，
that limits the maximum size of a packet.
它限制了数据包的最大大小。
And the other limitation is that,
另一个限制是，
if you send huge packets,
如果你发送巨大的数据包，
that means that all the routers in host of all have to have huge packet buffers
这意味着主机中的所有路由器都必须有巨大的数据包缓冲区，
to be prepared to receive huge packets
才能准备好接收巨大的数据包，
and that starts to get an really expensive,
这开始变得非常昂贵，
because it's difficult to have variable length buffers,
因为很难有可变长度的缓冲区，
is most convenient to have just a single length of buffer
所以最方便的是只有单一长度的缓冲区，
and that works best,
这样效果最好，
if the maximum packet length isn't too enormous.
如果最大数据包长度不是太大。
Anyway, so for you think for,
不管怎样，对于你来说，
so Ethernet has 1500 9000 bytes limit,
所以以太网有 1500 , 9000 字节限制，
in addition you know for all these IP protocols have length fields which are 16 bits,
此外，对于所有 IP 协议都具有 16 位的长度字段，
so even if you are willing to have Ethernet have larger packet size,
所以，即使你愿意让以太网有更大的数据包大小，
IP itself has a kind of [] in maximum packet size is 64 kilobytes.
IP 本身也有最大数据包大小 64 千字节。
Okay.
好的。
Okay, good, so much for UDP.
好的，对 UDP 来说挺多了。
And hopefully when you finish the lab,
希望当你完成实验后，
you'll see output very much like this,
你会看到非常类似的输出，
in particular, the message from xv6
具体地说，来自 xv6 的消息，
and a message of reply back from the host that you're running running QEMU.
以及来自你正在运行的 QEMU 的主机的消息。
In fact, actually at the end of the lab,
事实上，在实验的最后，
you'll use,
你将使用，
you'll run software which we provide
你将运行我们提供的软件，
which will actually send a DNS query to Google's DNS servers
软件将向 Google 的 DNS 服务器发送 DNS 查询，
and get the response back our software, print response,
把回应拿回我们的软件，并打印响应，
your software will done the sort of Ethernet level device driver interactions.
你的软件将完成以太网级设备驱动程序交互。
Alright, so that's story for packet headers and protocols on the wire.
好的，这就是关于网络上的数据包报头和协议的事。
So corresponding to these packet formats is,
所以，与这些数据包格式对应的是，
let's call the stack of a network software that runs on the host,
让我们查看在主机上运行的网络软件堆栈，
so, if you think about what's sitting inside the host
所以，如果你想一想主机里有什么，
and you know from now on,
从现在开始，
I'm talking I mostly talk about sort of typical software arrangements,
我要说的主要是一些典型的软件安排，
there's all kinds of different ways people structured network software,
人们构建网络软件有不同的方法，
and it's somewhat quite different from what I'm gonna talk about,
和我要说的有点不同，
I'm going to talk about kind of,
我要讨论一下，
what I think is at least as a sort of standard approach.
我认为至少是一种标准的方法。
So let's assume we're running Linux, or maybe xv6,
让我们假设运行的是 Linux 或者是 xv6 ，
now we have a bunch of applications,
现在我们有一堆应用程序，
maybe a web browser,
可能是网络浏览器，
it maybe a DNS server,
也可能是 DNS 服务器，
who knows what bunch of applications,
谁知道是什么样的应用程序，
they all use the sockets API
它们都使用套接字 API ，
to open up file descriptors in the sockets layer,
来打开套接字层中的文件描述符，
so there's going to be this, inside the kernel,
所以在内核里会有这样的东西，
a layer of software called the sockets layer
称为套接字层的软件层，
that remember has tables,
它记住表，
that remembers the correspondence between file descriptors,
它记住对应的文件描述符，
which the applications read or write
应用程序用来读取，
and UDP port numbers or TCP port numbers
UDP 端口号或 TCP 端口号，
which is for the, the sort of endpoints of conversations that these file descriptors refer to,
是这些文件描述符引用的端点，
so the socket layer has these tables of file descriptors on port numbers
所以，套接字层有关于端口号的文件描述符表，
and it also typically has a queue of packets that have arrived
并且它通常还具有已到达的数据包队列，
and are waiting to be read by each socket or file descriptor.
并等待每个套接字或文件描述符读取。
And the software we provide you as a very primitive sockets layer,
我们提供的软件是一个非常原始的套接字层，
underneath that are gonna be the UDP and TCP protocol layers.
在它下面是 UDP 和 TCP 协议层。
UDP has almost nothing going on,
UDP 几乎什么都没发生，
it basically looks at incoming packets,
它查看传入的数据包，
extracts the destination port number
提取目的端口号，
and hands the packet off to the socket layer to,
并将数据包传递给套接字层，
so that payload is queued on the correct file descriptors incoming queue.
所以有效载荷在正确的文件描述符入站队列上排队。
TCP actually is much more complex,
TCP 实际上要复杂得多，
it keeps state for each TCP connection,
它保持每个 TCP 连接状态，
and it remembers all kinds of sequence numbers and packets
它会记住所有序列号和数据包，
that haven't been acknowledged and need to be retransmitted
那些没有确认和需要重发的，
to the huge amount of state and what's called protocol control block of TCP
以及 TCP 的大量状态和所谓的协议控制块，
and virtually no state in the UDP layer.
而在 UDP 层中没有状态。
These are often called transport layers, UDP and TCP
这些通常称为传输层， UDP 和 TCP ，
and we provide you with a simple UDP layer,
我们为你提供一个简单的 UDP 层，
but not a TCP layer,
而不是 TCP 层，
underneath TCP and UDP is IP layer,
在 TCP 和 UDP 下面是 IP 层，
which is often fairly simple,
这是相当简单的，
and kind of in parallel with the IP layer,
与 IP 层并行，
I'm not sure whether I should draw on the same level or underneath it,
我不确定否应该画在同一层面或下一层面，
is the ARP layer,
那就是 ARP 层，
under them both, we can think of as an Ethernet layer,
在它们下面，我们可以认为是以太网层，
but it's really there's not typically a separate Ethernet layer,
但实际上不会有单独的以太网层，
typically there's one or more NIC drivers at the lowest layer
通常在最低层有一个或多个网卡驱动程序，
and these talk to the actual NIC network interface hardware,
并且这些设备与实际的网络接口硬件通信，
which itself has a connection of to the local area network,
它本身有与局域网的连接，
or whatever kind of network attached,
或任何连接的网络，
and sort of at this level,
在这个层面上，
what happens is the packet arrives of the network,
发生的情况是数据包到达网络，
the NIC you know pulls it off the network,
网卡会把它从网络上拉下来，
hands it off to the driver
把它交给驱动，
and the driver essentially pushes the network the packet up the networking stack,
并且驱动将数据包向上推送到网络堆栈，
at each layer in the stack,
在堆栈中的每一层，
the you know that layer's header,
这一层的报头，
you know the IP layer will look the IP header,
IP 层会查看 IP 报头，
verify the headers, stripped off header UDP,
验证报头，从报头剥离出 UDP ，
UDP will figure out what file descriptor,
UDP 将找出文件描述符，
queue the data on and add it to that queue,
找出数据并放到队列中，
so packets come in and are parsed
数据包进入并解析，
and headers are stripped on the way up.
报头在向上的过程中被剥离。
And when an application sends a packet,
当应用程序发送数据包时，
the reverse thing happens,
会发生相反的事情，
as the packet moves down through the layers,
随着分组在各层中向下移动，
more and more headers are added on,
越来越多的报头被添加上，
until you get to the bottom layer
直到你到达最底层，
and then the packets handed the NIC for transmission.
然后数据包交给网卡进行传输。
So, of course the software,
所以，当然软件，
the way people think about and design network software
人们思考和设计网络软件的方式，
and the kernel is typically driven by the nesting of the protocols inside the packets.
内核通常由数局包内协议的嵌套来驱动。
Any questions about this structure?
对这个结构，有什么问题吗？
It's actually one important thing
实际上，有一个重要的事情，
that I kind of left out here, that sits on the side,
我留在这里，它在旁边，
there's buffers, there's packet buffers all through this,
这里有缓冲区，所有都通过这里，
when a packet arrives, it's copied into a packet buffer
当一个包到达时，它被复制到包缓冲器中，
and the packet buffers are sent up and down the stack
数据包缓冲器在堆栈中上下发送，
and there's often quite a few packet buffers,
而且通常有相当多的数据包缓冲器，
there's often queues between these layers,
这些层之间经常有队列，
there's certainly a queue here,
这里肯定有队列，
packets waiting to be processed by applications,
数据包等待应用程序处理，
and this will be a linked list of buffers,
这里是链表缓冲区，
and so there's a buffer allocator,
所以这里有一个缓冲区分配器，
that's a buffer scheme and a buffer allocator,
这是一个缓冲区方案和一个缓冲区分配器，
that's used throughout the stack,
在整个堆栈中使用，
and in the software, we give you a buffer scheme is called, MBUFs,
在软件中，我们给出了一个缓冲区方案，叫做 MBUF ，
so it's kind of MBUF scheme,
它是一种 MBUF 方案，
that's not a layer, but is used all throughout these layers.
这不是一个层，而是所有这些层都在使用。
Okay, this is the layering diagram of typical network stack.
好的，这是典型的网络堆栈分层图。
For this paper, it's actually important to understand how the control flow works,
对于论文来说，理解控制流是如何工作的很重要，
which is maybe a little bit different from what's in that diagram.
这可能与图中的有所不同。
One thing to know about networks stacks,
关于网络堆栈，需要了解的一件事是，
there's typically multiple independent actors,
通常有多个独立的参与者，
that process packets and take input,
处理数据包并接受输入，
think about those packets and produce output
考虑这些数据包并产生输出，
and for various reasons, these different actors are decoupled,
由于各种原因，这些不同的参与者是分离的，
so they can run concurrently and have packet queues connecting them.
所以它们可以并发运行，并具有连接它们的数据包队列。
So that's extremely important from the point of view this paper,
所以从论文的角度来看，这是非常重要的，
so within the kernel,
所以在内核中，
so again, we have a network interface card,
同样，我们有一个网卡，
and then we have the kernel,
然后我们有内核，
the classic arrangement here is for the NIC to somehow get packets,
经典安排是让网卡以某种方式获取数据包，
for the NIC when it receives a packet to generate an interrupt
对于网卡，当它接收到数据包时会生成中断，
and there's this interrupt routine,
这里有一个中断例程，
that gets triggered whenever there's an interrupt
当中断来时就会触发，
and the job of the interrupt routine is to get the packet from the NIC.
中断例程的任务是从网卡中获取数据包。
And because we don't want to dedicate CPU time
因为我们不想专门拿出 CPU 时间
to completing the processing of the packet now,
用于完成数据包的处理，
the interrupt routine typically just appends the packet to a queue of packets,
中断例程通常仅将数据包附加到队列，
for later processing, and then return,
以便稍后处理，然后返回，
so does the minimum work required
所以，所需的最少工作是
to get the packet from the NIC and put it in a queue
从网卡获取数据包并将其放入队列中，
and the reason why we want to transfer in the sort of traditional network stack,
我们要转移到传统的网络堆栈中的原因，
we want to quickly move the packet out of the NIC and into this software queue
我们希望快速将数据包从网卡中移出并移入这个软件队列，
is the NIC typically have a very limited amount of memory for queue in packets,
因为网卡通常只有非常有限的用于数据包队列的内存，
whereas in the main memory, the RAM of the computer,
而在主内存，计算机的 RAM 中，
we might have gigabytes of memory,
我们可能有千兆字节的内存，
so far more space here,
所以这里有大得多的空间，
so the NIC,
所以，网卡，
so if there's a burst of packets
所以，如果出现数据包突发，
and NIC may actually run out of space to queue them,
网卡可能没有空间对它们进行排队，
so we copy them this queue here
所以，我们将它们复制到这里的队列，
to avoid the NIC running out of space.
以避免网卡空间不足。
And then separately perhaps in a separate thread,
然后可能在单独的线程中，
there's what I call the IP processing thread,
这里有我所说的 IP 处理线程，
and sometimes it's not a thread,
有时它不是一个线程，
sometimes it's sort of different kind of entity,
有时它是一种不同的实体，
but its basic job is to read packets of these incoming queues
但它的基本工作是读取这些传入队列的数据包，
and there may be multiple NICs,
而且可能有多个网卡，
you know appending packet to these queues,
将数据包追加到这些队列，
so IP thread runs,
所以 IP 线程运行，
it looks at packets that are queued here
它会查看在这里排队的数据包，
and decides what to do with them.
并决定如何处理它们。
One possibility is to send them up through UDP into the sockets layer
一种可能是通过 UDP 将它们向上发送到套接字层，
to be queued waiting for some application
排队等待某个应用程序，
and typically this will just be a function calls here
通常在这里只是一个函数调用，
within the context of this thread.
在这个线程的上下文中。
Another possibility,
另一种可能，
and this is the possibility the paper cares most about is that
这也是论文关心的可能性是，
this host is actually a router
这个主机是一台路由器，
and it's packets are coming in one NIC
它的数据包从一个网卡进入，
and routed out one or more other NICs,
然后从一个或多个其他网卡路由出去，
because it's very common to build routers out of ordinary operating systems, like Linux,
因为在普通操作系统上构建路由器是很常见的，比如 Linux ，
if you buy a WiFi box now or a cable modem router or something,
如果你购买 WiFi 盒子或有线调制解调路由器或其他设备，
it's extremely likely to be running Linux internally
它很有可能在内部运行 Linux ，
and to use the standard Linux stack,
并使用标准 Linux 堆栈，
which has a complete router implementation,
它有完整的路由实现，
it's highly likely to be using that standard Linux stack in order to do its routing.
它很可能使用标准 Linux 堆栈来进行路由。
So if the IP thread looks at the destination IP address
所以，如果 IP 线程查看目标 IP 地址，
and decides I should send this out,
决定我应该把这个发送出去，
I should forward this packet out you know out another network interface,
我应该把这个包从另一个网络接口转发出去，
it'll add the packet to a queue of outgoing packets for this outgoing interface
它会将数据包添加到这个传出接口的传出数据包队列中，
and there's almost certainly,
几乎可以肯定的是，
so this is a receive interrupt, RX for receive,
这是一个接收中断， RX 表示接收，
there's usually some sort of transmit interrupt scheme for the outgoing NIC,
传出网卡通常有某种传输中断方案，
that and NIC will interrupt,
网卡将会中断，
whenever it's finished sending one packet
每当发送完一个数据包，
and is ready to be handed more packets,
并准备好接收更多数据包时，
these outgoing interrupts may also be important.
这些传出中断也很重要。
And the point here is that,
这里的重点是，
there's a bunch of concurrent entities,
这里有一堆并发的实体，
there's sort of separately scheduled in various different ways,
有各种不同方式的独立调度，
these interrupts are triggered by the NICs
这些中断由网卡触发，
asking for interrupts when packets arrive or when packets have been sent,
当数据包到达或发送是，发生中断，
this thread maybe a kernel thread like we have in xv6,
这个线程可能是我们在 xv6 中拥有的内核线程，
in a uniq processor,
在单个处理器中，
as was the case with today's paper,
比如在今天论文中的情况，
this thread can't run at the same time,
这个线程不能同时运行，
as interrupt, interrupt absolute priority,
中断有绝对优先级，
on a multi-core machine, there may be more parallelism
在多核计算机上，可能会有更多的并行性，
and then it's important that applications to be able to read the packets,
然后，重要的是应用程序要能够读取数据包，
the applications are yet another independently scheduled entities,
应用程序是另一个独立调度的实体，
that we'd like to get the chance executing on the CPU.
我们希望得到机会在 CPU 上执行。
So these are all the players in the, and that's in the scheduling game essentially.
所以这些是在调度游戏中的所有玩家。
One thing that comes up a lot is buffering,
有一件经常出现的事是缓冲区，
so there's a three queues here,
所以这里有三个队列，
by buffering, I mean,
通过缓冲，我指的是，
these structures in which one append, it appends input packets
这些结构附加输入数据包，
and some other entity polls packets of the front of the queue,
并且一些其他实体轮询队列前面的数据包，
these queues are pervasive in networking systems.
这些队列在网络系统中无处不在。
One reason for them is
其中一个原因是
to allow temporary to cope temporary bursts,
为了应对临时性的突发，
this IP thread maybe can only process packets at however any per second,
这个 IP 线程可能只能以每秒多少的速度处理数据包，
but the NIC may be able to deliver packets much more quickly
但是网卡可能能够更快地传送数据包，
and so there may be a little sort of temporary burst of packets,
所以这里可能会有一些临时的数据包突发，
we'd like to have somewhere to put them
我们希望有一个地方存放它们，
waiting for the IP thread to get around to processing
等待 IP 线程开始处理，
and so that's one use of queues,
这是队列的一种用途，
on the output side,
在输出端，
another use of queues as we'd like to,
我们希望使用队列的另一种方式，
especially if packets are bursting,
特别是如果数据包突发，
we'd like to be able to stack up a bunch of packets here,
我们希望能够在这里存放一些数据包，
ready for the NIC to send,
准备网卡发送，
to keep the NIC to output NIC busy,
保持输出网卡忙，
because depending on the speed of things,
因为根据速度的不同，
it may be quite important
它很重要，
to be able to hunt to utilize 100% of the network here.
能够在这里以 100% 利用网络。
And the other reason for it,
另一个原因是，
maybe the same reason stated differently for having queues is
也许与排队的原因不同，
to be able to structure software into independent parts that are scheduled separately,
能够将软件组织成单独调度的独立部分，
wouldn't necessarily want to have our IP thread or the application
不需要 IP 线程或应用程序
know about the other things that have to go on,
知道必须进行的其他事情，
like interrupt processing,
比如中断处理，
so the IP thread is sort of a traditional networking system,
所以 IP 线程是一种传统的网络系统，
it doesn't necessarily know when interrupts happen or when applications run,
它不需要知道中断何时发生或应用程序何时运行，
although we'll see in this paper,
虽然我们将在这篇论文中看到，
that there may be advantages to having a little bit of knowledge there.
在那里有一点了解可能是有好处的。
Questions about this scheduling control diagram?
对于这个调度控制图，有什么问题吗？
Oh, I have a question,
哦，我有个问题，
so can the same NIC now be used for both transmitting and receiving?
同一个网卡能不能同时用于发送和接收？
It can so my laptop really only has one interface
它可以，实际上我的笔记本电脑只有一个网卡，
and it connected to WiFi,
它连接到 WiFi ，
when it receives a packet,
当它收到一个数据包，
this on my laptop,
在我的笔记本电脑上，
this NIC is actually a WiFi radio interface,
这个网卡是一个 WiFi 无线电接口，
packets arrive and go out on the same NIC.
数据包在同一网卡上到达和传出。
The two NIC situation is certainly used for routers,
两个网卡的情况用于路由器，
so your home WiFi,
所以你家里的 WiFi ，
I don't know, maybe I have WiFi and cable
我不知道，也许我有 WiFi 和有线，
and there's a router box, that has two NICs,
还有一个路由器盒子，它有两个网卡，
one is the its connection to my cable modem,
一个连接到我的电缆调制解调器，
which leaves the rest of the Internet
剩下的是互联网，
and the other one is my WiFi Interface,
还有一个是我的 WiFi 接口，
so that the little box,
所以这个小盒子，
that the cable modem cable [] sent me
电缆调制解调器发送，
as a router with two network interfaces.
作为一个路由器有两个网络接口。
And there's actually a lot of servers have multiple interfaces also,
实际上很多服务器也有多个接口，
especially ones that are web servers,
尤其是那些 web 服务器，
that you want to talk to the outside world,
你想要与外部世界交互，
well, one interface sent your private sensitive database machine or something
一个接口发送到你的私有敏感数据库机器或其他什么，
on a totally separate network with another network interface,
在具有另一个网络接口的完全独立的网络上，
this arrangement is pretty common.
这种安排是相当常见的。
So the criteria for having multiple NICs is
所以，有多个网卡的原则是
just wanting to talk to different networks then.
想与不同的网络通信。
Yeah, if you want to talk to different networks,
是的，如果你想与不同的网络通信，
then you have multiple NICs, yes.
那么你有多个网卡，是的。
Alright, I wanna as I said,
好的，像我所说的，
talk a little bit more about NICs,
多谈一点关于网卡的事情，
what NICs do with packets when they arrive,
网卡在数据包到达时如何处理它们，
and this is a special relevance to the lab.
这与实验有关系。
You you know what NIC looks like internally,
网卡内部是什么样子，
you know it's got a cable leading or a radio leading to the from the outside world,
它有一根电缆或无线电从外面的世界通向那里，
you know it looks at electrons as they come in
当电子进来的时候，它查看它们，
and sort of turns them into packets.
把它们变成数据包。
And then there's the host,
然后这里是主机，
and there's the host some sort of driver software in it,
主机里面有某种驱动软件，
and one way or another,
不管怎样，
you know we need to get a packet that's decoded in the NIC into memory
我们需要将在网卡中解码的数据包放入内存，
where the IP software and the host can parse that packet
其中 IP 软件和主机可以解析这个数据包，
and so there's a lot of different schemes been designed over the years,
所以这些年来设计了很多不同的方案，
the paper scheme is that the NIC has a lot of internal memory,
论文的方案是网卡具有很多内存，
and as packets arrive,
当数据包到达时，
the only, the only immediate thing that happens is
唯一立即发生的事情是
that NIC puts you know lays down the packets in its own buffer memory,
网卡将数据包放入自己的缓冲存储器中，
that's it.
就是这样。
And interrupts the host the host
并且中断主机，
and said that the NIC has an internal queue of packets and a bunch of memory
网卡有一个内部的数据包队列和一堆内存，
and then in the interrupt in the host driver,
然后在中断，在主机驱动程序中，
the host driver has a loop in it,
主机驱动中有一个循环，
the host driver will talk to them,
主机驱动程序会与它们交互，
they can say you know any packets buffered,
它们可以说任何缓冲的数据包，
and if it does,
如果是这样，
now the host has a loop,
主机有一个循环，
that will just copy you know by byte or word by word,
它会逐个字节或逐个字地复制，
copy this packet into the memory of the host
将这个数据包复制到主机的内存中，
and appended to a queue inside the host,
并附加到主机内部的队列中，
so that's how the paper's NIC works,
所以这就是论文中网卡的运作方式，
the drivers is responsible for doing the copy from NIC memory to host memory.
驱动程序负责执行从网卡内存复制到主机内存。
That made a lot of sense 30 years ago,
这在 30 年前很有意义，
today though it turns out that loops in the CPU that copy,
今天，在 CPU 中复制的循环
that you know talk to external hardware or hardware sitting on buses are very very slow,
与外部硬件或在总线上的硬件交互非常非常慢，
this sort of you know in the grand scheme of microprocessor design,
在微处理器设计的宏观方案中，
this distance here between the CPU and an external device,
CPU 和外部设备之间的距离，
even if it's on the same computer,
即使它在同一台计算机上，
this is a very long distance
这是一段非常远的距离，
and each conversation today takes a long time
今天的每一次交互都需要很长的时间，
to reach back for chit chat
互相交互，
and so you don't want to have a lot of byte interaction,
所以你不想有太多的字节交互，
so people don't design high-speed interfaces like this anymore.
所以人们不再设计这样的高速接口了。
So a much more modern arrangement looks like this,
所以一个更现代的安排看起来是这样的，
so now I'm gonna talk about an arrangement
所以，现在我要讨论一种安排，
which shows up in the E1000 NIC,
在 E1000 网卡上的一种安排，
which you'll use in the lab or simulation of it.
你将在实验中使用或模拟它。
So, you know the way the E1000 NIC works,
所以， E1000 网卡的工作方式，
so has this wire and it's looking at the electrons,
有这根电线，它查着电子，
but as the packets arrive,
但当数据包到达时，
the NIC writes them,
网卡写入它们，
NIC doesn't really have significant internal buffering,
网卡没有显著的内部缓冲，
although it has a little bit,
尽管它有一点，
it actually copies the packets directly into host memory
它将数据包直接复制到主机内存中，
where they'll be sitting there in host memory,
在那里，它们在主机内存中，
waiting for the driver to pick them up sort of already copied,
等待驱动把已经复制好的它们取走，
but that means that NIC has to know where memory it should put each packet,
但这意味着网卡必须知道它应该将每个数据包放在哪里，
so, the way that E1000 NIC works is
所以， E1000 网卡的工作方式是
that the host software formats up what's called rings,
主机软件格式化所谓的环，
DMA rings, a packet pointers,
DMA 环，一个数据包指针，
so DMA ring is just an array of pointers to packet buffers.
所以 DMA 环是指向数据包缓冲区的指针数组。
So the host host driver when it's initialized,
所以，当主机驱动程序初始化时，
the card will allocate however many say 16 1500 byte packet buffers
网卡分配比如 16 1500 字节数据包缓冲区，
will create an array of 15 pointers or 16 pointers
创建一个由 15 个或 16 个指针组成的数组，
and make these pointers point to there
并使这些指针指向那里，
and then it'll tell the NIC in configuration time,
然后它会在配置时告诉网卡，
look, here's the ring,
看，这是环，
so this is called DMA ring,
所以这叫 DMA 环，
because after you've gone off the end,
因为在你走出终点之后，
you start back at the beginning.
你又回到了起点。
The drivers software will tell the NIC,
驱动程序软件会告诉网卡，
here's a pointer the address in my RAM of the ring, DMA ring,
这里有一个指针指向 RAM 中的地址， DMA 环，
you're supposed to use the deposit incoming packets,
你可以用来寄存进来的数据包，
when a packet arrives,
当数据包到达时，
the NIC actually remember which ring entry is the next one,
网卡会记住下一个环条目，
it is a little pointer here,
这是一个指针到这里，
that allows it to remember the next entry,
这允许它记住下一个条目，
that it [should] DMA,
它[应该] DMA ，
packet into when a packet arrives,
当数据包到达时，
the NIC will fetch the pointer out of this,
网卡从这里提取指针，
fetch this buffer pointer out of the host RAM,
从主机 RAM 中获取缓冲区指针，
copy the packet bytes into this buffer
将数据包字节复制到这个缓冲区中，
and then advance its internal index here,
然后推进其内部索引到这里，
to point to the next ring slot,
指向下一个环的槽，
which we'll use for the next packet.
我们将在下一个包中使用它。
And there's a similar,
还有一个类似的，
so this will be RX ring,
所以这是 RX 环，
to receive,
为了接收，
there's a similar ring that the driver sets up
驱动程序设置了一个类似的环，
in which the driver puts packets,
驱动程序可以放入数据包，
that it wants the NIC to send,
它想让网卡发送，
so the NIC also has a pointer to the TX ring.
所以，网卡还有一个指向 TX 环的指针。
So you'll learn, your job in the lab is
所以你会学到，你在实验的工作是
basically to write the driver software that handle these rings.
编写处理这些环的驱动软件。
Any questions about this arrangement?
对于这个安排，有什么问题吗？
Yeah, how does the E1000 compare with production level NICs
是的， E1000 与生产级别的网卡相比，
that may be used in high performance environments.
可能在高性能环境中使用的。
Well when the E1000 came out,
当 E1000 出现时，
it was the absolute best NIC available
它绝对是最好的网卡，
and it was the NIC that was used in serious production environments,
它是在生产环境中使用的网卡，
but that was many years ago,
但那是很多年前的事了，
modern NICs are quite a bit clever,
现代网卡更聪明，
the what hasn't changed that much is this DMA ring structure,
变化不大的是这个 DMA 环结构，
you're still find that NICs to use DMA to deliver packets
你仍会发现网卡使用 DMA 传输数据包，
and the way they find the place to deliver the packets
它们找到递送数据包的地方的方式，
by these rings of buffer pointers.
通过缓冲区指针环。
The main there's a couple things that are that modern NICs more clever about,
有几件事是现代网卡更聪明的，
one is that modern NICs,
一个是现代的网卡，
you can set them up with many many queues,
你可以给它们设置很多很多的队列，
the E1000 I think just as a single receive queue,
我认为 E1000 只有单个接收队列，
but you can tell a modern NIC,
但是你可以告诉现代网卡，
look, you know I I want you to split my packets up into 32 different incoming queues
我想让你把我的数据包分成 32 个不同的传入队列，
and here's how to decide for each packet,
这里是如何为每个数据包做出决定，
look at this field
查看这个字段，
and use that to choose which ring DMA the packet to,
并使用这个字段选择数据包 DMA 环，
and there's a whole bunch of clever ways that people use that capability
有很多聪明的方式让人们使用这种能力，
like if you have multiple virtual machines,
比如，如果你有多个虚拟机，
your Amazon and you're running many guest virtual machines,
你的亚马逊，并且你正在运行多个客户虚拟机，
you may use that capability
你可以使用这个能力，
to sort of direct each packet to the queue corresponding to the virtual machine,
将每个数据包定向到与虚拟机对应的队列，
that that packet should be read by.
那个数据包应该被读（的虚拟机）。
Another way in which modern NICs more clever
另一种现代网卡更聪明的方式，
as they'll do some of the TCP processing on the NIC,
它们在网卡上执行一些 TCP 处理，
like maybe typically checksum calculations the most I think.
我想最多的可能是通常的校验和计算。
Anyway, yeah,
无论如何，是的，
so, modern NICs like the E1000 but more.
现代网卡类似 E1000 ，但是更多。
Okay, thanks.
好的，谢谢。
Oh, sorry good.
哦，抱歉，好的。
Oh, yeah, I just wanted to ask,
哦，是的，我想问一下，
so in our scheme in the lab,
在我们实验的方案中，
there, there is no queue between the IP layer and the driver, right?
在 IP 层和驱动之间没有队列，是吗？
Yeah the lab network stack is stripped down to the absolute minimum,
是的，实验网络堆栈被精简到绝对最小，
simpler in structure than a real networks stack.
结构比真正的网络堆栈更简单。
But this is worse in terms of performance?
但就性能而言，这是否更糟糕？
Oh, I don't know, I've never run it in real life,
哦，我不知道，我从来没有在现实生活中运行过它，
I'm sure they've certainly we paid zero attention to performance,
我敢肯定，我们肯定没有注意性能，
when writing lab networks,
当编写网络实验时，
so it would be surprising if this performance,
所以如果有高性能是令人惊讶的，
but mostly it's not a question of performances limitations,
但大多数情况下，这不是性能限制的问题，
it doesn't do 95% of what you need network stack to do,
它不能达到你需要的 95% 的网络堆栈，
like handle multiple NICs or have TCP.
比如处理多个网卡或使用 TCP 。
Right, right,
对，对，
okay I see, thank you.
好的，我明白了，谢谢。
Um, sorry, so, were there any like hardware changes to the overall system,
嗯，抱歉，对于整个系统有没有硬件变动，
that were needed to enable like NICs to have direct memory access,
需要让网卡可以直接访问内存，
like in the previous picture,
像上一张图那样，
was everything needed through the CPU
是否所有内容都通过 CPU ，
or could NICs also reached the that memory directly.
或者网卡是否也可以直接到达内存。
In that picture I showed before,
在我之前展示的那张图片中，
you know the NIC doesn't reach the memory at all, the.
网卡访问不到内存。
Okay.
好的。
I actually don't know,
我实际上不知道，
I mean the the,
我的意思是，
maybe the most important question is
也许最重要的问题是，
how virtual memory whether and how virtual memory translation works,
虚拟内存转换是否以及如何工作，
when NIC wants to use an address that refers to host memory
当网卡要使用引用主机内存的地址时，
and I don't actually know how that works,
我不知道它是怎么工作的，
I I suspect there's a translation,
我猜这里有一个转换，
you know NIC is really sitting on a bus,
网卡实际在总线上，
that's connected with,
它连接到，
you know through some fairly intelligent silicon to the to the DRAM system
通过一些智能的硅连接到 DRAM 系统，
and I believe in modern machines,
我相信在现代机器中，
you can setup translation tables within NIC,
你可以在网卡内设置转换表，
could use virtual addresses
可以使用虚拟地址，
or addresses that are translated by this hardware that sits between it and RAM,
或者由这个位于它和 RAM 之间的硬件转换的地址，
and that could be very valuable for some situations.
在某些情况下，这可能是非常有价值的。
The other thing,
另一件事，
I mean another thing that I'm aware of is that,
我是说，我意识到的另一件事是，
if the NIC is going to write some memory or read some memory
如果网卡要写入一些内存或读取一些内存，
and the memory is cached on the CPU,
并且内存被高速缓存在 CPU 上，
you, you know you want the NIC to read,
你想让网卡读取，
if, if the software just wrote a packet buffer,
如果软件只是写入一个数据包缓冲区，
but the CPU hasn't,
但是 CPU 没有，
the CPU is merely cached the write,
CPU 只是缓存了写，
because after all, most memories write back,
因为在之后，所有内存被写回，
that means that the real latest version of that memory
这意味着内存的最新版本
is sitting in the CPU cache not in RAM
位于 CPU 缓存中，而不是在 RAM 中，
and in that case,
在这种情况下，
we'd like the NIC to be reading the CPU cache, not the RAM,
我们希望它读取 CPU 缓存，而不是 RAM ，
if it does DMA
如果它执行 DMA ，
and certainly on Intel machines and probably on others,
当然，在英特尔的机器上，也可能在其他机器上，
there's some fairly elaborate machinery,
有一些相当复杂的机制，
so that if the NIC read some memory,
如果网卡读取一些内存，
but the latest copy that memories in the CPU cache,
但是内存的最新副本位于 CPU 缓存中，
it's the CPU cache that will produce the data and not RAM.
CPU 缓存将产生数据，而不是 RAM 。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah, that's actually a facility,
是的，那实际上是一种设施，
you can some clever software uses to get high performance,
一些聪明的软件来获得高性能，
that is to have the effect of having this happens for writes also,
也就是说，对于写入也会发生这种情况，
that the NIC will essentially directly write cache lines in the cache,
网卡直接在高速缓存中写入高速缓存线，
where it's the CPU can get at the data very quickly.
CPU 可以非常快速地获取数据。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Simple, but their real life it's pretty involved.
简单，但它们在现实生活却相当复杂。
Other questions about, about anything?
还有别的问题吗？
Okay, I'd like to switch gears now to today's paper.
好的，我现在想换个话题看今天的论文。
And I'm just gonna like,
我只想说，
because we've already talked about the sort of a lot of the background of this paper,
因为我们已经讨论了很多这篇论文的背景，
I'm just going to go directly to the first graph paper
我要直接转到论文中的第一个图，
and essentially to drive the discussion of of the paper's graphs
为了推动对论文图表的讨论，
and so what we're looking at here is the performance graph for router,
我们现在看到的是路由器的性能图，
on on the x axis,
在 x 轴上，
there's a router with two NICs,
这里有一个带有两个网卡的路由器，
its job is to packet receive in one NIC
它的工作从一个网卡接口数据包，
and it's supposed to just send them out the other NIC.
并把它们从另一个网卡发送出去。
The x axis is the arrival rate,
x 轴是到达率，
which packets arrive at the input NIC,
数据包到达输入网卡，
and the y axis is the output rate
y 轴输出率，
at which packets are observed to leave the output NIC
观察到数据包离开输出网卡，
and the line we care about is
我们关心的线是，
is the filled circles which goes up then down.
是填充的圆，向上然后向下。
So even without knowing anything about what's going on here,
所以即使对这里发生的事情一无所知，
we can look at this graph
我们可以看看这张图，
and we can ask ourselves,
我们可以问问自己，
gosh, why does it go up, why does it go down,
为什么它上升，为什么它下降，
you know what's special about this point, that's an inflection,
这一点有什么特别之处，这是一个拐点，
you know what is it that governs how fast it goes up or how fast it goes down.
是什么决定了它上升的速度或者下降的速度。
So even with zero knowledge,
所以即使是零知识，
we kind of have a good clue about what questions to ask,
我们也有很好的线索知道该问什么问题，
so why does it go up,
那么为什么它会上升，
why does it go up?
为什么它会上升？
It's not a very deep question.
这不是一个很深奥的问题。
They go up, sorry, go ahead.
它们上去，对不起，请继续。
Oh, I guess when they're like, until it gets saturated,
哦，我想直到它饱和时，
you can process more input packets and produce more output packets.
你可以处理更多的输入包并生成更多的输出包。
Absolutely, until something starts to go wrong,
当然，在事情开始出错之前，
for every packet that comes in, the router just forwards it out,
对于进入的每个包，路由器只是将它转发出去，
so you know until things go wrong,
所以，直到事情出了问题，
if packets arrive at 2000 packets a second,
如果数据包以每秒 2000 个的速度到达，
well, it just copies every input packet to the output
它只是将每个输入数据包复制到输出，
and that means that the output rate is just equal to the input rate,
这意味着输出速率正好等于输入速率，
so this is why y equals x,
所以这是为什么 y 等于 x ，
because every input packet gets sent out,
因为每个输入包都被发送出去，
so it's y equals x for a while.
所以有一段时间 y 等于 x 。
And so why does it stop going up?
那么为什么它停止上升？
Isn't this the one thing they mentioned in the paper about,
这是不是他们在论文上提到的一件事，
the they're being interrupts that can't be processed at the necessary rate.
它们无法以需要的速率处理中断。
That's the answer to the question, why does it go down.
这是它为什么会下降的问题的答案。
My question is why does it stop going up, what is it,
我的问题是，为什么它停止上升，是什么，
that could this line in a well designed system,
这个线在设计良好的系统中，
supposing that they hadn't messed up the design, right,
如果他们没有搞乱设计的话，
you and I would design a system that didn't have problems, right,
你和我会设计一个没有问题的系统，
would our system with the line, just keep going up.
我们的系统会不会跟上这条线，继续往上走。
I guess not,
我想不会，
because at some point the rate at which packets come will,
因为在某一时刻，数据包到达的速率将会，
if you can process packets fast enough,
如果你可以足够快地处理数据包，
then at some point,
那么在某一点上，
the bottleneck will be the rate at which packets arrived.
瓶颈将是数据包到达的速率。
That's right, this system we're talking about has has some sort of limits,
对，我们现在说的这个系统是有一些限制，
you know the CPU is not infinitely fast,
你知道 CPU 不是无限快的，
CPU executes, however many instructions per second and no more,
无论 CPU 每秒执行多少条指令，不会更多，
so usually these packets has to be processed,
所以通常这些数据包必须被处理，
the IP software has to look at the header and check the checksum
IP 软件必须查看报头并检查校验值，
and look up the destination addresses and table whatever it takes,
并查找目地的址和它使用的表，
hundreds or thousands of CPU cycles per packet.
每个数据包需要数百或数千个 CPU 周期。
And so we can never never expect these lines to go up
所以我们不能指望这个线永远会上升，
and definitely it must stop somewhere, right
它肯定会在某个地方停下来，
and we can sort of tell what,
我们可以确定，
we can make some guesses,
我们可以猜测，
on this system that goes up to 5000 and no more,
这个系统最高可达 5000 ，但不会更多，
and what that basically suggests to us is that
这向我们表明，
it takes about 200 microseconds on this computer to process each packet, right,
在这台计算机上处理每个数据包大约需要 200 微秒，
that's what this point,
这就是这一点，
the fact that the inflection point is here means
拐点在这里意味着
suggests that the total cost of processing package is around 200 microseconds CPU time.
处理包的总成本大约是 200 微秒的 CPU 时间。
It's a guess,
这是个猜测，
but it's likely to be close to correct
但很可能接近正确，
and so there's no way we could get,
所以我们不可能得到，
you know maybe we could make the software a little more efficiently,
也许我们可以把软件做得更有效率一些，
we could reduce that to 150 microseconds per packet or something,
我们可以将其降低到每个包 150 微秒，
and so maybe we could move the inflection point up a bit,
所以也许我们可以把拐点往上移一点，
but we're certainly faced with some point,
但是我们确实面临着一些点，
at which well that's just how many packets of this system can process.
就是这个系统可以处理的数据包的数量。
You know, that's not necessarily what's going on here,
这并不一定是这里正在发生的事情，
it happens to be what's going on here,
这是这里会发生的事情，
but it's not written in [],
但它不是写在[]上，
in fact the, there's other bottlenecks that could be the limit,
事实上，还有其他瓶颈可能是限制，
other than CPU time,
除了 CPU 时间，
which are worth considering the most obvious is the speed of the network,
值得考虑的最明显的是网速，
the network they were using ran at only ten megabits per second,
它们使用的网络仅以每秒 10 兆比特的速度运行，
that's just how fast the low level networking hardware sent bits
这就是低级网络硬件发送比特的速度，
and so can never transmit more than ten thousand ten million bits per second.
所以，每秒传输的位永远不会超过一万，一千万位。
And so that may also constitute a limit
所以，这也可能构成一个限制，
and so we're thinking about
所以我们考虑，
whether maybe that's actually what's determining this 5000.
这是否真的是决定这个 5000 的原因。
I don't, the paper doesn't quite say enough
我不知道，论文上说的不够，
to know whether it's, whether it's CPU or the NIC is the limiting factor here,
知道是 CPU 还是网卡是这里的限制因素，
but the fact is with with their ten megabit network,
但事实是，它们的 10 兆网络，
if you send small packets,
如果你发送小数据包，
it's the ten megabits translates into something,
那就是 10 兆比特转换成某些东西，
like ten or 15 000 packets per second,
比如每秒 10000 或 15000 个数据包，
that's the limit that the networking cable puts on the input rate
这是网线对输入速率的限制，
and so this is well under the ten or 15 000 packets per second,
所以，这远远低于网络所能达到的每秒 10000 或 15000 个数据包，
that the network is capable of,
这个网络的能力，
so almost certainly,
所以，几乎可以肯定的是，
the limit has to do with CPU or memory or something
限制与 CPU 或内存或其他因素有关，
and not the, not the network itself.
而不是网络本身。
Okay.
好的。
What we'd love to see, in a well designed router is that
我们希望在一个设计良好的路由器中看到的是，
it can actually you know it takes 200 microseconds
它需要 200 微秒，
to forward the packet to process a packet,
来转发数据包，处理数据包，
what we'd like to see is
我们希望看到的是，
that the thing the router can actually forward 5000 packets per second, no matter what,
无论如何，路由器实际上每秒可以转发 5000 个数据包，
even if the load is high,
即使负荷很高，
so what we'd like to succeed is this line here.
所以我们想要的是这条线。
There's a output rate matches the input rate
这里有一个输出速率与输入速率相匹配，
until you get up to the capacity of the system,
直到你达到系统的容量，
you know 5000 packets per second
每秒 5000 个数据包，
and then it just continues to forward 5000 packets per second
然后它继续以每秒 5000 个数据包的速度转发，
and presumably drops discards the rest.
很可能丢弃其他的。
So this is what we'd like to design,
这就是我们想要设计的东西，
but what actually happened is much worse than that,
但实际发生的情况远比这更糟糕，
as you increase the rate beyond 5000,
当你将速率提高到 5000 以上时，
the number of packets that [] the forward goes down towards 0.
转发的数据包数量将降至 0 。
So why is this line go down,
那么为什么这条线往下走，
somebody mentioned this before.
之前有人提到过。
Well, the, there's a reason that the authors figured out is that
好的，作者想出了一个原因，
as you increase the input rate,
当你提高输入速率时，
each of these input packets generates an interrupt,
每个输入数据包都会生成中断，
and the interrupts take time,
而中断使用时间，
actually on their system interrupts are quite expensive,
实际上在它们的系统上，中断是相当昂贵的，
because they involve
因为它们涉及
copying a packet off of the network interface card and into main memory
将数据包从网卡复制到主内存中，
which took a long time,
这花了很长时间，
because the CPU was doing,
因为 CPU 正在做，
so each, so we know with packets arriving at 10 000 per second,
所以我们知道数据包以每秒 10000 个的速度到达，
we certainly can't forward 10,000,
我们当然不能转发 10000 个，
and that means the best we can hope for is to forward 5000,
这意味着我们最多只能希望转发 5000 ，
and simply discard the other 5000,
然后简单地丢弃剩下的 5000 ，
but in fact the extra 5000 packets,
但实际上额外的 5000 个包，
each generated very expensive interrupt,
每个包都会产生非常昂贵的中断，
so for each additional packet over 5000 per second,
所以，对于每秒 5000 个以上的额外数据包，
we're generating more and more expensive interrupts,
我们产生了越来越昂贵的中断，
which have priority,
它们有优先权，
like interrupts boy whatever you're doing,
中断不管你在做什么，
it stops the machine, takes the interrupt,
它会停止机器，接受中断，
because the machine is essentially giving priority these interrupts,
因为机器优先考虑这些中断，
that means every additional packet per second
这意味着每秒每个额外的数据包
is taking CPU time away from the forwarding code,
占用转发代码的 CPU 时间，
until finally 100% of the CPU time is used up in the input interrupt routine
直到最终 100% 的 CPU 时间在输入中断例程中用完，
and no CPU time is used in the thread that forwards packets.
并且没有 CPU 时间可以用在转发数据的线程上。
Is everyone happy with this explanation?
大家对这个解释满意吗？
And this going down, it's called interrupt live lock.
这个下降，就是所谓的中断活锁。
The fact that this line goes down instead of saying string [],
这条线下降，而不是直线，
what people mean by interrupt live lock
人们所说的中断活锁，
and it's actually a phenomenon that occurs in many systems,
这是一个在许多系统中都会发生的现象，
I mean the sort of thing that's driving it is
我的意思是驱动它的东西是，
that there's two separate tasks,
这里有两个不同的任务，
like the input interrupt task and the forwarding task,
比如输入中断任务和转发任务，
and because of a scheduling problem,
并且由于调度问题，
essentially priority is given to the input task,
优先考虑输入任务，
which can starve packet processing task,
会使包处理任务饥饿，
in pretty much any system that has multiple independent tasks
在几乎任何具有多个独立任务
or sort of sequence of independent tasks,
或一系列独立任务的系统中，
that need to be done to each input
这需要对每个输入完成操作，
and in which the input rate can't necessarily be controlled,
而输入率不一定是可控的，
many systems like that will exhibit exhibit live lock,
许多这样的系统都会显示活锁，
if you push them too hard.
如果太过用力。
And you can get live lock due to many resources not just CPU,
你会遇到活锁，可能因为多种资源，不仅是使用 CPU，
but it could be that the NIC,
它可能是网卡，
you know NIC DMAs uses up RAM cycles to do the DMAs
网卡 DMA 耗尽了 RAM 周期来执行 DMA ，
and if the NIC is using the RAM,
如果网卡正在使用 RAM ，
the CPU can't use the RAM,
CPU 就不能使用 RAM ，
so another way to get live lock,
所以另一种获得活锁的方法，
even if you have lots of CPU time,
即使你有很多 CPU 时间，
you know some other design, you might live lock,
一些其他的设计，你也可能会得到活锁，
because the NIC is using up RAM resources, RAM performance resources,
由于网卡正在耗尽 RAM 资源，
so the CPU was less able to use the RAM.
所以 CPU 使用 RAM 的能力变差。
Anyway, this line going down is what they mean by live lock.
不管怎样，这条线下降就是他们所说的活锁。
You may ask what happens to the extra packets
你可能会问，多余的数据包会发生什么情况，
and if you recall the structure of their software,
如果你回想一下他们的软件结构，
was that they had been NIC that basically feeds the receive interrupt,
它们有网卡，处理接收中断，
received interrupt software copies each packet into a queue,
接收中断软件复制每个数据包到一个队列，
and then there's some sort of network thread,
然后有某个网络线程，
that pulls packets off the queue,
将数据包从队列中拉出，
the exact place where packets are lost are right here.
数据包丢失的确切位置就在这里。
What's going to happen is that the interrupt routine,
接下来会发生的是中断例程，
once we get down here with serious live lock,
一旦因为活锁，下降到这里，
the interrupt routine is going to fill this queue,
中断例程将填充这个队列，
there's going to be some maximum queue length here,
这里会有最大队列长度，
you know, at least all the RAM, but probably much less.
至少所有的内存，但可能要少得多。
And the interrupt routine is going to pull a packet off the NIC
中断例程从网卡上拉出一个数据包，
and see that this queue is already as long as it's allowed to be
看到这个队列已经达到了允许的长度，
and the interrupt routine will discard the packet,
中断例程将丢弃数据包，
but then of course immediately after that,
当然在那之后，
there'll be another interrupt,
还会有另一次中断，
the interrupt routine will again discard the next packet,
中断例程将再次丢弃下一个数据包，
because the network thread is always interrupted and never allowed to run.
因为网络线程总是被中断，并且永远不允许运行。
Questions about this diagram?
关于这张图，有什么问题吗？
This is the most important diagram in the paper.
这是论文中最重要的图。
Alright, well we've basically run out of time,
好的，我们快没时间了，
so I'll try to compress the answer to this problem into a minute,
所以我会试着把这个问题的答案压缩到一分钟内，
the authors proposed a solution,
作者提出了一个解决方案，
the most immediately good news about the solution is
关于这个解决方案最直接的好消息是，
that this is the performance of their solution,
这是他们的解决方案的性能，
that is the input rate goes up to the 5000,
也就是说，输入率上升到 5000 ，
and then its flat 5000 regardless of input rate.
然后是平坦的 5000 ，无论输入率是多少。
So this is sort of a perfect non live lock performance line,
所以这是一条完美的非活锁性能线，
of course it's going to be flat,
当然会是平坦的，
because you can only process 5000 packets per second,
因为你每秒只能处理 5000 个数据包，
the speed of the CPU
CPU 的速度，
and the way they get this,
他们得到这个的方式，
they still have this network thread,
他们仍然有这个网络线程，
and they still have an interrupt routine.
而且他们仍然有一个中断例程。
So the very first time the NIC interrupts run the interrupt routine,
所以，当第一次网卡中断时，运行中断例程，
but the interrupt routine does not copy packets off the NIC,
但是中断例程不从网卡复制数据包，
it wakes up the network thread
它唤醒网络线程，
and then leaves interrupts on the NIC disabled,
然后使网卡上的中断处于禁用状态，
so we'll get no more interrupts,
所以我们不会再被中断，
wake up the networking thread and then the interrupt routine will return,
唤醒网络线程，然后中断例程返回，
so now interrupts of this NIC turned off,
所以现在这个网卡中断关闭，
the network thread basically has a loop,
网络线程有一个循环，
that you know check the NIC,
它检查网卡，
you know pull a few packets from the NIC,
从网卡中提取几个数据包，
5, I think is what they ended up using
5 个，我想这是他们最终使用的，
and then process those packets.
然后处理这些数据包。
And then if there were none,
如果没有的话，
if this you know check,
如果这个检查，
then it's this network thread you know that reads packets off the NIC,
这个网络线程从网卡读取数据包，
not the interrupt routine,
而不是中断例程，
if there none, no packets waiting,
如果没有等待的数据包，
it enables interrupts, and then goes to sleep,
它会启用中断，然后进入休眠状态，
because it's enabled interrupts,
因为它启用了中断，
next time packet arrives,
下次数据包到达时，
interrupt routine will wake up this thread
中断例程将唤醒这个线程，
and come out of sleep and go back to the top of loop.
从睡眠中醒来，回到循环的开端。
So this is, this is the structure of their solution
这就是他们解决方案的结构，
and one way to view this is,
看待这个的一种方式是，
that they turn an interrupt scheme into a polling scheme,
他们将中断方案转变为轮询方案，
that is under high load,
在高负荷的情况下，
they just sit in this loop,
它们只是在这个循环里，
and they read packet process, read packet process, with interrupts turned off,
它们在中断关闭的情况下读取包并处理，读取包并处理，
so they since interrupts are turned off,
因为中断是关闭的，
they never get this effect,
所以永远不会有这个效果，
where the interrupts steal time from the main thread,
中断从主线程窃取时间，
whereas under low load, they enable interrupts,
而在低负载下，它们启用中断，
and may be a while until packets arrive,
在数据包到达之前可能需要一段时间，
but they'll be woken up by the interrupt routine immediately
但是，它们会立即被中断例程唤醒，
if a packet does arrive.
如果一个数据包到达。
And that's all I have to say.
这就是我要说的全部。
Any questions?
有什么问题吗？
I have a question,
我有个问题，
is that loop looking at all of the devices
这个循环是查看所有设备，
or only the one that generated the interrupt?
还是只查看生成中断的设备？
If there's multiple NICs,
如果有多个网卡，
so that's a good question,
这是一个好问题，
if there's multiple NICs, the loop,
如果有多个网卡，这个循环，
I don't actually know how the how the loop works,
我其实不知道循环是如何工作的，
a very reasonable design is for this network thread to keep track of,
一个非常合理的设计是让这个网络线程跟踪，
for every NIC whether it's an interrupting mode or polling mode,
对于每个网卡，无论是中断模式还是轮询模式，
and then it will only,
然后它只会，
actually, because the interrupt routines no longer read packet from the NIC,
实际上，因为中断例程不再从网卡读取数据包，
that means the loop probably checks every interface at this point,
这意味着在这一点上循环可能会检查每个网卡，
every probably checks every NIC at this point,
在这一点上，可能检查每个网卡，
then pulls up,
然后拉出，
for every NIC, it has a few packets,
对于每个网卡，它都有几个数据包，
packet if that NIC has packets waiting,
如果网卡有数据包在等待，
loop will pull a few out of the NIC and process them
循环将从网卡中取出几个并对其进行处理，
and then if none of the NICs had anything,
如果所有的网卡都没有，
if you checked all the NICs
如果你检查了所有网卡，
and none of them at any packets waiting,
但没有任何数据包在等待，
the loop will enable interrupts on all the NICs and sleep,
这个循环将在所有网卡上启用中断，然后休眠，
and any NIC interrupts will wake it up,
任何网卡中断都会唤醒它，
that's my guess.
这是我的猜测。
Okay, yeah, sounds reasonable.
好的，听起来很合理。
I had a quick question then,
我有一个简短的问题，
so how did the, so while the loop is running,
当循环运行时，
how do packets actually get into the queues to be pulled,
数据包是如何进入要拉取的队列的，
I felt like there would only be one at a time.
我觉得一次只有一个。
Initially the, initially the packets are queued inside the NIC in its own private memory,
数据包最初在网卡内部的私有内存中排队，
then this loop,
然后这个循环，
you know when it when it goes back to the top of the loop,
当它回到循环的开端时，
it'll look at each NIC,
它查看每个网卡，
and actually talk to the NIC hardware
并与网卡硬件通信，
and asked do you have any input packets waiting in your memory,
询问内存里有没有什么输入包在等待，
and if it does,
如果是这样，
then this loop will, will you know allocate a packet buffer in RAM
那么这个循环将在 RAM 中分配一个数据包缓冲区，
and copy the bytes of the packet out of the NIC to the packet buffer
并将数据包中的字节从网卡复制到数据包缓冲区，
and then process that packet buffer.
然后处理那个数据缓冲区。
So it can copy more than one packet.
所以，它可以复制多个数据包。
Yeah, I think they do it in groups of 5,
是的，我想它们是以 5 个一组的，
in order to,
为了，
even if there's a hundred packets waiting here,
即使这里有一百个包在等待，
it would just process the next 5,
它只处理接下来的 5 个，
in order to be fair among input NICs to avoid starving.
以便在输入网卡之间保持公平，从而避免饥饿。
But this requires increasing the memory capacity of the NIC, right, possibly?
但这可能可能需要增加网卡的内存容量，是吗？
Well, I don't know,
嗯，我不知道，
I don't know how much,
我不知道多少，
the NIC might have had a reasonable amount of,
网卡可能有相当数量的，
the thing is this interrupt,
这个中断的问题是，
you know this live lock phenomenon below this point where probably interrupting,
这个活锁现象，在这个点以下，可能是在中断，
and, if a packet arrives,
如果数据包到达，
the network thread will almost immediately be woken up
网络线程将立即被唤醒，
and pull the packet out,
并将数据包拉出，
over here in this machine,
在这里，在这个机器中，
where too many packets are arriving,
有太多的数据包到达，
and this loop is polling instead of interrupting,
这个循环在轮询，而不是中断，
packets are gonna be lost, we just know that,
数据包会丢失，我们知道，
because the difference,
因为不同，
you know this difference between the the input rate and the output rate,
这个输入率和输出率之间的差别，
this is all dropped packets,
这都是丢弃的数据包，
adding, I don't think adding,
增加，我不认为增加，
because these packets are going to be dropped anyway,
因为这些数据包无论如何都会被丢弃，
adding buffering to the NIC doesn't probably doesn't help very much.
增加网卡缓冲区可能不会有太大帮助。
I I don't I don't think it's a NIC,
我不，我不认为网卡，
it's not clear that NIC needs more than small amount of buffering.
目前还不清楚网卡需要更多的缓冲区。
Yeah, that makes sense,
是的，有道理，
yeah, you only need as much as it would need to take to get saturated.
是的，你只需要达到饱和所需的量就行了。
So you know I think in their design,
所以，我想在他们的设计中，
they would pull 5 packets,
它们会拉出 5 个包，
of the quota was 5 packets
配额是 5 个包，
and so the NICs centainly needs 5 packets of buffering,
所以网卡需要 5 个数据包缓冲，
that makes sense, but probably,
这是有道理的，但是可能，
anyway, it's not clear that more than that would be very beneficial.
无论如何，还不清楚比这更多是否会更好。
Really, the purpose of buffering is to absorb transient bursts,
实际上，缓冲区的目的是吸收瞬时突发，
whole packets is long enough that the software can get along to reading,
整个数据包足够长让软件可以继续读取，
but we're not talking about transient anything in this situation,
但在这种情况下，我们不谈论瞬变现象，
we're talking about persistent overload.
我们谈论的是持续性超载。
So there's that,
所以就是这样，
so that means there's not really much function for a lot of buffering.
这就意味着来提供大量的缓冲没有更多功能。
Yeah make sense.
是的，理解了。
I think my question is related to that,
我想我的问题与此有关，
it's, so if the difference between interrupts on and interrupts off here is that,
如果这里打开中断和关闭中断之间的区别是，
it's going to be the same,
它会是一样的，
but like it's still going to be putting things on the queue,
但它仍然会把东西放在队列上，
if it's able to,
如果它能做到的话，
but it will just not issue an interrupt,
但它不会发出中断，
but if there's no place on the queue,
但如果队列上没有位置，
then it will just drop.
那么它就会丢弃。
The interrupt, the interrupt routine in this new scheme never looks at packets.
这个新方案中的中断例程从不查看数据包。
Oh yes,
哦，是的，
I mean like, you said,
我是说，你说过，
you turn off the interrupts for the NIC, right.
你关闭了网卡的中断，对吧。
Yeah, so this what happens in the interrupt handler is,
是的，这里中断处理程序中发生的事情是，
it disables interrupts on this NIC
它禁用这个网卡上的中断，
and then wakes up the network thread,
然后唤醒网络线程，
that's all it does, then returns.
这就是它所做的一切，然后返回。
Right, I guess my question is when the interrupt here disabled,
好的，我想我的问题是当中断禁用时，
can the NICs still put packets on its own buffer?
网卡是否仍然可以将数据包放在自己的缓冲区中？
Yes, the NIC is self-contained,
是的，网卡是独立的，
so it has internal buffering,
所以它有内部缓冲，
whether or not, regardless of whether interrupts are enabled or disabled,
无论是否启用或禁用中断，
the only, all that happens when a packet arrives is
当数据包到达时，唯一发生的事情是，
the NIC adds appends the packet to its queue of packets
网卡将数据包附加到它的数据包队列上，
in its own internal memory,
在它自己的内部内存中，
that's all that ever happens when a packet arrives.
这就是数据包到达时发生的所有事情。
So whenever the NIC, in this paper's NIC,
所以当网卡，在本论文的网卡中，
different designs are very different,
不同的设计是非常不同的，
but for this paper,
但对于这个论文，
their NIC never did DMA,
他们的网卡从未进行过 DMA ，
never reached out and touched host memory ever,
也从未接触过主机内存，
it kept an internal queue in its own memory
它在自己的内存中保留了一个内部队列，
and the hosts could read packets out if it wanted to.
如果主机愿意，可以读出数据包。
Okay, I see,
好的，我明白了，
and if there's no memory, then.
如果没有内存的话，那么。
Drop.
丢弃。
Okay.
好的。
So in this design,
所以在这个设计中，
if packets are these extra packets,
如果数据包是这些多余的数据包，
the place they're dropped is is inside the NIC,
它们被丢弃的位置是在网卡内，
what'll happen is a packet or [],
发生的是数据包或[]，
if we're an overload situation,
如果我们处于过载状态，
then the NICs queue will be full always or almost always,
那么网卡队列将总是或几乎总是满的，
and so when a packet arrives,
所以，当数据包到达时，
the NICs queue will typically be full,
网卡队列将是满的，
it will drop,
它将丢弃，
the NIC will drop the packet
网卡将丢弃数据包，
without wasting any CPU time on the machine.
而不会浪费机器上的任何 CPU 时间。
Okay, yeah.
好的，好的。
That the fact that it can drop without burning up CPU time here,
事实上，它可以在不消耗 CPU 时间的情况下丢弃，
is one way of explaining how they avoid live locks.
是解释它如何避免活锁的一种方式。
Right, right, okay, thank you so much.
好的，好的，非常感谢。
I had a quick question,
我有一个简短的问题，
will there ever be a scenario,
会不会有这样一种情况，
in which the CPU will pull a few packets,
在这种情况下， CPU 会拉出几个数据包，
but the like internal software queues are all like full.
但是内部软件队列都是满的。
Oh sure.
哦，当然。
Yeah, there's some other bottleneck,
是的，还有其他一些瓶颈，
so for example suppose these incoming packets,
比如，假设这些传入数据包，
some of them need to be delivered to some application on a socket,
其中一些需要传送到套接字上的某个应用程序，
if that application isn't reading packets fast enough,
如果那个应用程序读取数据包速度不够快，
then the socket buffer leading to
那么套接字缓存导致，
you know that that application should be reading will get full
那个应用程序正在读取的套接字缓冲区将被填满，
and then packets may be dropped in the networking thread,
然后数据包可能在网络线程中丢弃，
and that can also lead to live lock,
这也可能导致活锁，
because now because we have the same,
因为现在因为我们有相同的，
the reason live lock comes up is that
活动锁出现的原因是，
we expanded resources processing a packet that was later dropped,
我们扩展了资源处理数据包，后来被丢弃，
so it was wasted effort.
所以这是白费力气。
If the application is not reading it's,
如果应用程序没有读取它的，
well, one way we can get live lock is
好的，我们可以获得活锁的一种方法是，
as the load goes up,
随着负载的增加，
maybe we end up spending a 100% of our time in the networking thread,
也许我们使用 100% 的时间在网络线程上，
leaving 0% of the time for whatever application is supposed to be reading the packets
为应该读取数据包的应用程序留出 0% 的时间，
and then we'll again get live lock.
然后我们会再次得到活锁。
But it won't be interrupt live lock,
但它不是中断活锁，
it will be network processing live lock or something,
它是网络处理活锁或其他什么，
the paper actually has a story for that,
这个论文有关于这方面的描述，
somewhere in section six,
在第六部分的某个地方，
they talk about the network,
他们谈到了网络，
if packets are being delivered to a local application,
如果数据包被递送到本地应用，
the network thread would look at the socket queue for that application,
网络线程将查看那个应用的套接字队列，
and if it was getting long,
如果它变长了，
it would turn off interrupt would turn off interrupts
它会关闭中断，
and stop pulling packets off the network interface
并停止从网络接口拉出数据包，
until the queue got shorter.
直到队列变短。
And and so that means that network thread would stop running
这意味着网络线程将停止运行，
and give the application a chance to run and process the packets,
给应用程序一个运行和处理数据包的机会，
so you can get live lock like situations at any stage,
所以你可以在任何阶段得到活锁，
if you're not careful in a multistage process scheme.
如果你在多阶段处理方案中不小心的话。
OK, that makes sense, thank you.
好的，有道理，谢谢。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Welcome.
不客气。